<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>campus on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/campus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in campus on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/campus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Campus</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/land-donated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/land-donated/</guid>
      <description>Thanks mainly to the donation and fund-raising work of Nathaniel FitzRandolph—son of an “original Quaker settler”–Princeton outbids New Brunswick for 1,700 New Jersey pounds in funding, ten acres of “cleared” land for the campus, and 200 acres of woodland for fuel. FitzRandolph alone donates 4.5 acres. There is no recorded consultation between Nathaniel FitzRandolph’s ancestors and the Lunaapeew. Likewise, there is no mention of the Lunaapeew in the documents detailing the enormous “land donation” from the people of Princeton to the College of New Jersey in the mid-1700s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonel George Morgan</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</guid>
      <description>Colonel George Morgan is appointed Agent of Indian Affairs by the Continental Congress. Morgan is proprietor of Prospect Farm and future friend of Lunaape Chief White Eyes.
Nassau Literary Magazine clipping on Colonel George Morgan, authored by Raymond Fosdick in 1906.Daily Princetonian Princeton Weekly Bulletin clipping on George Morgan White Eyes, authored by Caroline Moseley in 1992.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Stays at Prospect</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/guardian/</guid>
      <description>Son of Chief White Eyes and Rachael Doddridge, George Morgan White Eyes, and his two cousins (the Killbuck brothers) are put in the care of Indian Agent and namesake George Morgan at his Prospect Farm. George Morgan was close friend of the slain Chief White Eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous/Settler Conference</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/conference/</guid>
      <description>“Indigenous/Settler” conference examines methods for thinking across geographies, building alliances, and fighting settler colonialism at large without abandoning attention to specific histories and struggles. Located on the site of Lunaapahkiing—and from the ground of Princeton’s colonial establishment—the conference explores and historicizes what has been called “trans” or “pan” or “global” Indigenous studies.&amp;quot;
See the poster for the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.
Browse photos from the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunaapahkiing</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapahkiing means “lands of the Lenape” in the Munsee (Lunaape) language. It is Lunaape ancestral homeland since time immemorial and includes the unceded grounds of Princeton University.
Delaware-English spelling book by David Zeisberger written in 1776.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassau Hall</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/nassau-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/nassau-hall/</guid>
      <description>In 1756, the construction of Nassau Hall is completed on FitzRandolph’s 4.5 acre donation and the College of New Jersey moves from Newark to Princeton. FitzRandolph proudly records this moment in his journal on November 13 1756: “Aaron Burr, President, preached the first sermon and began the school in Princeton College.” When built, the Nassau was the largest stone buildings in the Colonies and it is most likely where the University&amp;rsquo;s earliest Native students such as Jacob Wooley boarded (in 1759).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Convocation</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</guid>
      <description>During the surge of the American Indian Movement in the early 1970s, Princeton hosts the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March. Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Tewa) of Anthropology chairs the event. Considered by some to be the starting point for Native American Studies, a resolution by Native scholars called for an academic discipline that included Indian ways of knowing left out of European-American education.
Princeton prepares to host the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March 1970.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton University</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/princeton-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/princeton-university/</guid>
      <description>In 1896, the College of New Jersey is renamed Princeton University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Library Collection and Space</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/library-recognitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/library-recognitions/</guid>
      <description>A print collection opens on the first floor of Firestone Library focused on Indigenous Studies. The first shelf is a “living land acknowledgement” featuring books related to the Munsee community and relevant campus history. The other shelves feature voices of Indigenous authors. Visitors are encouraged to browse and borrow the books and to suggest additions to the collection, which includes materials from across the world. Natalie Diaz, Pulitzer-prize winning author, meets with Native graduate students in the space which is suitable for small conversational events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospect Occupation</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/occupation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/occupation/</guid>
      <description>Following the murder of Chief White Eyes, a delegation of ten Ohio Delaware leaders and their respective retinues assembles at Prospect Farm to assure the U.S. Government of continued loyalty and friendship. Read more about Prospect Farm at Princeton &amp;amp; Slavery.
Read a 1931 description of the 10 Delaware members who came to Prospect during Colonel George Morgan&amp;rsquo;s tenure of the farm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Cultural Collections</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/cultural-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/cultural-property/</guid>
      <description>Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, a graduate from the Princeton Theological Seminary, begins to donate Native American cultural belongings mostly from Alaska, the Pacific Northwest Coast, and the Southwest to the Princeton Theological Seminary. The collection is supplemented by additional Jackson donations in 1883 and 1885.
In 1886, William Libbey (‘1877) returns from an expedition in Alaska with Yakutat Tlingit material, including materials from a shaman’s grave. In 1882, the collection is transferred to the College of New Jersey, and the Museum of Geology and Archaeology (in what is now the faculty room in Nassau Hall), and subsequently to Guyot Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
