<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dispossession on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/dispossession/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dispossession on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/dispossession/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1866 Delaware Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</guid>
      <description>Following the Civil War, the Delaware continue to suffer under the pressure of increasing white settlement. The U.S. Government signs a final treaty with the Delaware Tribe, the 1866 Delaware Treaty. The Delaware Council “gives up” their reservation in Kansas and relocates to Indian Territory. Just under 1,000 Delaware remove to the Cherokee Nation at an area equal to 160 acres a person. The Delaware purchase a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River valley (Oklahoma-Kansas today).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of Fallen Timbers</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</guid>
      <description>Battle of Fallen Timbers (in present-day northwestern Ohio): Americans defeat intertribal confederacy of Delaware, Shawnee, and a number of other Indigenous forces. The Delaware in this instance are the Delaware who had remained in Ohio during the American Revolution and who become the Delaware Tribe of Indians. The battle leads to the Greenville Treaty the following year, in which most of Ohio Country would be ceded to the colonial Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Removal Act</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</guid>
      <description>Under President Andrew Jackson, the Indian Removal Act empowers the U.S. Government with the policy and funds used to “persuade, bribe, and threaten” Indigenous peoples into land-exchange treaties (“removals”) for lands assigned to them in “Indian Territory” west of the Mississippi. See the Indian Removal Act Exhibit.
Native Removal Act from May 28th, 1830.U.S. National Archives </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</guid>
      <description>The Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession Symposium reunites Tlingit scholars and artists with Tlingit belongings held at the Princeton University Art Museum. In the late nineteenth century, Presbyterian missionary Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, Professor William Libbey (class of 1877), and Lieutenant George T. Emmons brought hundreds of Tlingit belongings from southeastern Alaska to the Princeton Theological Seminary. Moving from the Department of Geosciences to the Art of the Ancient Americas, the institutional drift of these Tlingit belongings reflects an ongoing condition of broken knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treaty of Greenville</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</guid>
      <description>In the 1794 Jay Treaty between Britain and the United States, Britain withdraws their association with Native Americans south of Canada, weakening the position of pro-British Native Americans in the United States. Months later, the Delaware and several nations sign the Treaty of Greenville with the colonial Americans. For an annuity of approximately $9,500 they “cede” all but a patch of Ohio land, which the United States retains the right to purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Cultural Collections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</guid>
      <description>Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, a graduate from the Princeton Theological Seminary, begins to donate Native American cultural belongings mostly from Alaska, the Pacific Northwest Coast, and the Southwest to the Princeton Theological Seminary. The collection is supplemented by additional Jackson donations in 1883 and 1885.
In 1886, William Libbey (‘1877) returns from an expedition in Alaska with Yakutat Tlingit material, including materials from a shaman’s grave. In 1882, the collection is transferred to the College of New Jersey, and the Museum of Geology and Archaeology (in what is now the faculty room in Nassau Hall), and subsequently to Guyot Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Deceit</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</guid>
      <description>Not only is Thomas and John Penns&amp;rsquo; deed underlying the &amp;ldquo;Walking Purchase&amp;rdquo; itself highly suspect, but they recruit runners, not walkers, for the job of marking the extent of the purchase. Further, colonial agents clear a path for the runners in a reconnaissance of the territory beforehand. As a result, the Penn brothers seize 750,000 acres of Lunaape land.
View a depiction of Thomas Penn, one of the Penn brothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westward Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</guid>
      <description>The Walking Purchase is a key event in the forced migration of southern Lunaape communities westward into Ohio Country, shaping Lunaape/British relations for decades to follow.
A 1765 engraving by Thomas Hutchins showing where American military forces marched in a section of the Ohio River Valley, where native tribes were living.Library of Congress </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
