<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>treaties on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/treaties/</link>
    <description>Recent content in treaties on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/treaties/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1866 Delaware Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</guid>
      <description>Following the Civil War, the Delaware continue to suffer under the pressure of increasing white settlement. The U.S. Government signs a final treaty with the Delaware Tribe, the 1866 Delaware Treaty. The Delaware Council “gives up” their reservation in Kansas and relocates to Indian Territory. Just under 1,000 Delaware remove to the Cherokee Nation at an area equal to 160 acres a person. The Delaware purchase a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River valley (Oklahoma-Kansas today).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bartholemew Calvin (Shawukukhkung)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</guid>
      <description>In 1774 Bartholomew Scott Calvin (Shawukukhkung or Wilted Grass) (Lunaape) matriculates at the College of New Jersey. His father is Stephen Calvin, Native translator at the Treaty of Easton. Missionary David Brainerd from nearby Cranbury advocates for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s admission to College President John Witherspoon and Calvin is sponsored by the Scottish Society for the Propagation of Christian Knowledge. Funds are cut off in 1776 during the Revolutionary War, and Calvin has to drop out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of Fallen Timbers</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</guid>
      <description>Battle of Fallen Timbers (in present-day northwestern Ohio): Americans defeat intertribal confederacy of Delaware, Shawnee, and a number of other Indigenous forces. The Delaware in this instance are the Delaware who had remained in Ohio during the American Revolution and who become the Delaware Tribe of Indians. The battle leads to the Greenville Treaty the following year, in which most of Ohio Country would be ceded to the colonial Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Reservation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</guid>
      <description>Under the terms of the 1758 Treaty of Easton, the first Native reservation in the colonies, the Brotherton Reservation, is established near Medford Lakes, sometimes known as Indian Mills, New Jersey. Brotherton is intended to “accommodate” (or concentrate) Lunaapeew who refuse to leave their land. Missionary David Brainerd is appointed guardian of Lunaapeew now called Brotherton Indians.
1963 Princeton Herald article, by John T. Cunningham, describing the origins of Brotherton Reservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cherokee-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cherokee-purchase/</guid>
      <description>Following the Delaware Treaty, the Delaware Tribe purchases a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River Valley (Kènii Sipu, around the Oklahoma-Kansas border). Delaware chief John Conner writes to Cherokee Chief William P. Ross (1842 Princeton alum) confirming the sale and stating his choice of the “preservation” over “incorporation” option, consistent with the 1866 U.S. Treaty with the Cherokee of 1866. The Delaware Tribe preserves its tribal integrity, vouching to maintain tribal organization in ways not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the Cherokee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chief White Eyes</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/white-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/white-eyes/</guid>
      <description>Chief White Eyes (named Koquethagechton) is a principal chief among the Lunaapeew, and a key figure in maintaining tribal neutrality and protecting Native land during the American Revolution. Chief White Eyes is one of the signatories on the 1778 Treaty of Fort Pitt and marries Rachael Doddridge, an assimilated English woman captured in a Lunaape raid at age five. He works closely with and strikes up a friendship with Colonel George Morgan at Fort Pitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiefs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/chiefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/chiefs/</guid>
      <description>British and Iroquois compel Lunaapeew to appoint a single chief for negotiations, violating the established Lunaape system of shared authority among multiple sachems, or chiefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easton Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</guid>
      <description>During the Seven Years&amp;rsquo; War (1754 to 1763), Lunaapeew who have been forced into the Ohio Country (after the Walking Purchase) ally with the French. British colonial governors introduce the 1758 Treaty of Easton to Lunaapeew and other Native nations. The last of Lunaape land in New Jersey is “ceded” for $1,000 Spanish dollars.
At the signing of the Easton Treaty, the Lunaape representative Teedyuscung makes it clear that the deceit of the Walking Purchase had led Lunaapeew to fight against the British.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Removal Act</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</guid>
      <description>Under President Andrew Jackson, the Indian Removal Act empowers the U.S. Government with the policy and funds used to “persuade, bribe, and threaten” Indigenous peoples into land-exchange treaties (“removals”) for lands assigned to them in “Indian Territory” west of the Mississippi. See the Indian Removal Act Exhibit.
Native Removal Act from May 28th, 1830.U.S. National Archives </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shackamaxon Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</guid>
      <description>According to legend, William Penn enters into a treaty with Lunaapeew in 1682. The Treaty of Shackamaxon is signed under an elm tree in a sacred Lunaape area known as Shackamaxon, which is north of Philadelphia and along the Lenapewihittuck/Delaware River. Penn signs agreements with Lunaapeew that bring lands deeded to him under his absolute title, while still recognizing and reserving certain lands for Lunaapeew where their villages are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treaty of Greenville</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</guid>
      <description>In the 1794 Jay Treaty between Britain and the United States, Britain withdraws their association with Native Americans south of Canada, weakening the position of pro-British Native Americans in the United States. Months later, the Delaware and several nations sign the Treaty of Greenville with the colonial Americans. For an annuity of approximately $9,500 they “cede” all but a patch of Ohio land, which the United States retains the right to purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
