<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>library on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/library/</link>
    <description>Recent content in library on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brainerd&#39;s Otterskin Book</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</guid>
      <description>University President Jonathan Edward&amp;rsquo;s bound beaverskin book is presented to the University Library by Mrs. William Edwards. The Hebrew Lexicon (ca. 1645) with its beaverskin binding is likely the work of Lunaapeew for missionary David Brainerd. David Brainerd was a pioneer missionary among Native peoples after being expelled from Yale for his New Light Presbyterian beliefs and comments about an impious faculty member. He founded Bethel Indian Town (ten miles from Princeton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Faculty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</guid>
      <description>Princeton Anthropology Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Ohkay Owingeh Pueblo) publicly supports the American Indian Movement occupation of Wounded Knee. In 1970, Ortiz, chaired the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars, the first of its kind in Native American history. Arriving from the University of Chicago, where he completed his doctorate, Ortiz became a faculty member in 1967. Working with library curator Alfred Bush, he actively recruits undergraduates from the Southwest, many of whom live on reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on American Indian Affairs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</guid>
      <description>The Princeton University Library publishes the online collection of the American Indian Affairs records which includes over 240 digitized books and manuscripts, some selected by librarians and others requested by Indigenous researchers. Records include land deeds, missionary-created language dictionaries and translations of religious documents. Graduate students work with librarians to create searchable Munsee dictionaries from the newly-digitized books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on Indigenous Cultures</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</guid>
      <description>The University Library deepens its commitment to Indigenous studies with the newly organized Indigenous Studies Libguide, the Indigenous Cultures online collection, and a digitized collection of Lunaape/Delaware language items.
Browse items related to indigenous cultures and items specific to Lunaapee peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Library Collection and Space</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</guid>
      <description>A print collection opens on the first floor of Firestone Library focused on Indigenous Studies. The first shelf is a “living land acknowledgement” featuring books related to the Munsee community and relevant campus history. The other shelves feature voices of Indigenous authors. Visitors are encouraged to browse and borrow the books and to suggest additions to the collection, which includes materials from across the world. Natalie Diaz, Pulitzer-prize winning author, meets with Native graduate students in the space which is suitable for small conversational events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
