<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>language revitalization on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/language-revitalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in language revitalization on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/language-revitalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Language Alliance</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Princeton’s Indigenous Language Alliance is a community for individuals at Princeton and beyond who are learning or would like to learn Indigenous languages and who are interested in language revitalization. Its members hope to support language revitalization efforts among Native communities and increase access to language-learning opportunities for Native students. The alliance includes graduate students, undergraduates, librarians, Princeton faculty and staff, scholars from the Institute for Advanced Study, and language learners from other universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language &amp; History Symposia</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</guid>
      <description>The inaugural Munsee Language &amp;amp; History Symposium at Princeton in 2021 is the first event to bring “Princeton faculty and students in direct dialogue with members of the Munsee-Delaware Nation.&amp;quot; Language keepers Karen Mosko and Ian McCallum, historian Mark Peters, and a number of Native activists and artists lead discussions of Munsee language, history, and culture. The second symposium in October 2022 commemorates Mosko and Peters who passed away just months earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunaape Language Camp</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-camp/</guid>
      <description>Munsee language teachers organize a Delaware (Lunaape) language camp with Princeton and IAS faculty. The gathering includes teachers from all of the Munsee-speaking nations, along with young adult community members who may become future teachers. The schedule includes traditional land-based learning, including time at the Seed Farm located in Princeton (which is a collaborative partnership with Ramapough Lunaape Nation members), as well as a half-day journey on the Millstone River, sharing Lunaape language, local history, and discussions of Indigenous sovereignty in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial of Historian Mark Peters</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</guid>
      <description>Mark Peters, Munsee–Delaware Nation member who served his people in many different roles, was a dedicated historian who shared his knowledge within the community and far beyond, both through his travels and through online video lectures. Those at Princeton will long remember his time on Lunaapahkiing, along with his daughter Katelyn, for the inaugural Munsee Language and History Symposium in November 2021. Together with Ian McCallum, he spent time with Lunaape language items and Munsee land documents at Firestone Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Delaware Story Evening: NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Delaware Story Evening, or NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories), is an annual event hosted by the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey. During this virtual gathering, Munsee-Delaware Nation community member Ian McCallum shares stories from the community in both the Munsee and English languages. McCallum discusses the background to the stories as well as the active and ongoing interpretation and translation process. Artist Katherine Chupik-Hall shares the artistic approach to illustrating the stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Names Project</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-names/</guid>
      <description>Melissa Moreton, Caitlin Rizzo, and Suzanne Conklin Akbari describe the Munsee Names Project as “an Indigenous-led effort to support rediscovery and reclamation of the names of historical Munsee peoples - names and histories that have largely been lost, erased, or presented through the perspective of non-Indigenous peoples across the historical record.” The project began in November 2021 under Mark Peters (historian, knowledge keeper, and member of the Munsee Delaware Nation in Ontario), in collaboration with scholars and archivists at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on American Indian Affairs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</guid>
      <description>The Princeton University Library publishes the online collection of the American Indian Affairs records which includes over 240 digitized books and manuscripts, some selected by librarians and others requested by Indigenous researchers. Records include land deeds, missionary-created language dictionaries and translations of religious documents. Graduate students work with librarians to create searchable Munsee dictionaries from the newly-digitized books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
