<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Munsee on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/munsee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Munsee on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/munsee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Nation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>Group of both Unami and Munsee speakers migrate further west to a settlement near what is today Cape Girardeau, Missouri, at the invitation of the Spanish (Cape Girardeau Delawares later settle in Texas and eventually end up on a reservation with Caddo and Wichita communities in present-day western Oklahoma – recognized today as Delaware Nation).
Princeton Herald passage from August 1963 describing the Delaware move to Oklahoma.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minisink</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/minisink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/minisink/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Lunaapeew live along the Upper Delaware, in a region called Minisink, and along Muhheakantuck, or the “Hudson.” The land that became “Princeton” is likely home to both Munsee and Unami. “Unami” is how the Munsee refer to their relatives in the south, and “Munsee” is how the Unami refer to their relatives in the north.
Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing the Unami.Princeton Recollector Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing why the Minisink Trail has its name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee in Wisconsin</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Small groups of Christian Munsee and Unami converts remaining along the Hudson and Delaware River valleys relocate with Munsee and Mahicans living in Stockbridge, Massachusetts, to a reservation in Wisconsin. They are recognized today as Stockbridge-Munsee Band of Mohican Indians. Among those who moved to Wisconsin was Bartholemew Calvin who matriculated at the College of New Jersey in 1774.
Passage about the Stockbridge Lenape moving to Wisconsin in a Princeton Herald passage written in April 1963 by John Cunningham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Three Sisters Farm</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Three Sisters Farm is created to rebuild community and well-being among Munsee Ramapough clans after centuries of colonial violence, beginning with the Ramapough massacre in 1644 and continuing through a century of state-sanctioned industrial poisoning. The Turtle Clan, for instance, has lived for 56 years in a federal superfund site. The farm cultivates healthy traditionally grown food for distribution at no cost to the community while also earning a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Munsee</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/ontario-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/ontario-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Following the American Revolution in the late 1700s, some pro-British Munsee groups living in northwestern Ohio during the American Revolution migrate to Munceytown along Thames River (Ontario). They were known previously as the Munsee of the Thames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramapough Lenaapeew</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/ramapough-lenape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/ramapough-lenape/</guid>
      <description>Munsee-speaking clans live in communities on ancestral lands across the northeast New Jersey-New York border. Nearby Dutch from New Amsterdam attack and kill approximately 700 Native people in what becomes known as the Pound Ridge Massacre in effort to force out these communities.
Visit the Ramapough Culture and Land Foundation website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
