<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Princeton lands on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/princeton-lands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Princeton lands on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/princeton-lands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assunpink Trail</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</guid>
      <description>Route 27, Nassau Street in Princeton, is a Lunaape trail called the Assunpink, meaning “rocky, watery place.” European settlers find the trail useful since it connects two rivers—the Raritan and Lenapewihittuck, which Europeans name the Delaware. Over centuries, the Assunpink Trail is New Jersey’s main North-South roadway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</guid>
      <description>Thanks mainly to the donation and fund-raising work of Nathaniel FitzRandolph—son of an “original Quaker settler”–Princeton outbids New Brunswick for 1,700 New Jersey pounds in funding, ten acres of “cleared” land for the campus, and 200 acres of woodland for fuel. FitzRandolph alone donates 4.5 acres. There is no recorded consultation between Nathaniel FitzRandolph’s ancestors and the Lunaapeew. Likewise, there is no mention of the Lunaapeew in the documents detailing the enormous “land donation” from the people of Princeton to the College of New Jersey in the mid-1700s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenland Tavern</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</guid>
      <description>In 1683, the Henry Greenland Tavern is established along the Assunpink Trail, equidistant from the settlements of Philadelphia and New York. 1683 is the settlement date declared on the “Welcome to Princeton” signs today. Although the University declares that the “settlement” date is 1696, by then “Princeton” lands have been lived on for millennia by Lunaapeew.
1987 Town Topics article description of Henry Greenland.Princeton University Library View a map of early Stony Brook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous/Settler Conference</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</guid>
      <description>“Indigenous/Settler” conference examines methods for thinking across geographies, building alliances, and fighting settler colonialism at large without abandoning attention to specific histories and struggles. Located on the site of Lunaapahkiing—and from the ground of Princeton’s colonial establishment—the conference explores and historicizes what has been called “trans” or “pan” or “global” Indigenous studies.&amp;quot;
See the poster for the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.
Browse photos from the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingston</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</guid>
      <description>In 1709, a Jedediah Higgins “buys” one thousand acres from Lunaapeew next to the Assunpink Trail in an exchange for a sow and piglets. This land becomes the settler town of Kingston, which neighbors Princeton.
1983 Princeton Recollector article describing Jedediah Higgins.Princeton University Library View a photo of Jedediah Higgins House.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenapewihittuck</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</guid>
      <description>By the early 1600s, Lunaapeew have lived along Lenapewihittuck and its tributaries for millennia. Lenapewihittuck means “rapid stream of the Lunaape.” English settlers name it the “Delaware” after Lord de la Warr III, governor of the Virginia colony. Later, settlers refer to both the Munsee and the Unami Lenape as the “Delaware&amp;quot; – people of Lenapewihittuck.
1963 Princeton Herald article describing the origins of the Lenape.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunaapahkiing</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapahkiing means “lands of the Lenape” in the Munsee (Lunaape) language. It is Lunaape ancestral homeland since time immemorial and includes the unceded grounds of Princeton University.
Delaware-English spelling book by David Zeisberger written in 1776.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton University</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-university/</guid>
      <description>In 1896, the College of New Jersey is renamed Princeton University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Yong</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/yong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/yong/</guid>
      <description>In 1634, Lunaapeew encounter the English captain, Thomas Yong, in the area now called Princeton.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
