<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lenapewihittuck/Delaware River on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/lenapewihittuck/delaware-river/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lenapewihittuck/Delaware River on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/lenapewihittuck/delaware-river/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assunpink Trail</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/assunpink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/assunpink/</guid>
      <description>Route 27, Nassau Street in Princeton, is a Lunaape trail called the Assunpink, meaning “rocky, watery place.” European settlers find the trail useful since it connects two rivers—the Raritan and Lenapewihittuck, which Europeans name the Delaware. Over centuries, the Assunpink Trail is New Jersey’s main North-South roadway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenapewihittuck</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</guid>
      <description>By the early 1600s, Lunaapeew have lived along Lenapewihittuck and its tributaries for millennia. Lenapewihittuck means “rapid stream of the Lunaape.” English settlers name it the “Delaware” after Lord de la Warr III, governor of the Virginia colony. Later, settlers refer to both the Munsee and the Unami Lenape as the “Delaware&amp;quot; – people of Lenapewihittuck.
1963 Princeton Herald article describing the origins of the Lenape.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minisink</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/minisink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/minisink/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Lunaapeew live along the Upper Delaware, in a region called Minisink, and along Muhheakantuck, or the “Hudson.” The land that became “Princeton” is likely home to both Munsee and Unami. “Unami” is how the Munsee refer to their relatives in the south, and “Munsee” is how the Unami refer to their relatives in the north.
Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing the Unami.Princeton Recollector Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing why the Minisink Trail has its name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NJ Nanticoke</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/nj-nanticoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/nj-nanticoke/</guid>
      <description>Nanticoke live along the Delaware River and unite with the Lunaapeew in New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Penn</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/wm-penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/wm-penn/</guid>
      <description>In 1682, William Penn lands in the “Delaware Bay” on a ship bearing smallpox pathogens. By then, the land has been designated as William Penn’s by English King Charles II to resolve an enormous debt to Penn’s father. Penn already holds lands in West and East New Jersey. Approximately 1,750 British Quakers now live in West New Jersey.
View a depiction of William Penn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
