<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quakers on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/quakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quakers on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/quakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Campus</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</guid>
      <description>Thanks mainly to the donation and fund-raising work of Nathaniel FitzRandolph—son of an “original Quaker settler”–Princeton outbids New Brunswick for 1,700 New Jersey pounds in funding, ten acres of “cleared” land for the campus, and 200 acres of woodland for fuel. FitzRandolph alone donates 4.5 acres. There is no recorded consultation between Nathaniel FitzRandolph’s ancestors and the Lunaapeew. Likewise, there is no mention of the Lunaapeew in the documents detailing the enormous “land donation” from the people of Princeton to the College of New Jersey in the mid-1700s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</guid>
      <description>Willim Penn hopes to make a profit from purchasing and selling lands and by collecting taxes. Yet his Quaker values oblige him to treat Lunaapeew equally. He demands of his fellow Quakers that “no man shall … in word or deed, affront or wrong any Indian.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Jersey Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-purchase/</guid>
      <description>In 1677, Quakers “purchase” all Lunaape land from Sassackon (Timber Creek) to Rancocas Creek, between the Atlantic Ocean and the Delaware River. The deal is made with Chief Katemus Sekappio. Payment is in the form of thirty guns, thirty axes, thirty hoes, thirty jewsharps, one hundred fishhooks, brandy, and other trinkets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Penn</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</guid>
      <description>In 1682, William Penn lands in the “Delaware Bay” on a ship bearing smallpox pathogens. By then, the land has been designated as William Penn’s by English King Charles II to resolve an enormous debt to Penn’s father. Penn already holds lands in West and East New Jersey. Approximately 1,750 British Quakers now live in West New Jersey.
View a depiction of William Penn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
