<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen Calvin on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/stephen-calvin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stephen Calvin on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/stephen-calvin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bethel Mission</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/bethel-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/bethel-mission/</guid>
      <description>In 1746, Presbyterian minister David Brainerd founds Bethel Indian Town, or the Bethel Mission Settlement, comprised of Lunaapeew who have converted to Christianity. Brainerd dies from tuberculosis a year later, but Bethel Mission does not disband until 1759. The Bethel site is about fifteen miles east of Princeton, in what is now Monroe Township. Brainerd is also mentor to Stephen Calvin (Lunaape), a Native translator at the Treaty of Easton; and he advocated for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s son Bartholemew Scott Calvin to matriculate at Princeton in 1774.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easton Treaty</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</guid>
      <description>During the Seven Years&amp;rsquo; War (1754 to 1763), Lunaapeew who have been forced into the Ohio Country (after the Walking Purchase) ally with the French. British colonial governors introduce the 1758 Treaty of Easton to Lunaapeew and other Native nations. The last of Lunaape land in New Jersey is “ceded” for $1,000 Spanish dollars.
At the signing of the Easton Treaty, the Lunaape representative Teedyuscung makes it clear that the deceit of the Walking Purchase had led Lunaapeew to fight against the British.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
