<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>William Penn &amp; brothers on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/william-penn-brothers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in William Penn &amp; brothers on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/william-penn-brothers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</guid>
      <description>Willim Penn hopes to make a profit from purchasing and selling lands and by collecting taxes. Yet his Quaker values oblige him to treat Lunaapeew equally. He demands of his fellow Quakers that “no man shall … in word or deed, affront or wrong any Indian.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dutch in Princeton</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-princeton/</guid>
      <description>In 1737, the Penn brothers sell Princeton area land to Dutch farmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shackamaxon Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</guid>
      <description>According to legend, William Penn enters into a treaty with Lunaapeew in 1682. The Treaty of Shackamaxon is signed under an elm tree in a sacred Lunaape area known as Shackamaxon, which is north of Philadelphia and along the Lenapewihittuck/Delaware River. Penn signs agreements with Lunaapeew that bring lands deeded to him under his absolute title, while still recognizing and reserving certain lands for Lunaapeew where their villages are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Deceit</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</guid>
      <description>Not only is Thomas and John Penns&amp;rsquo; deed underlying the &amp;ldquo;Walking Purchase&amp;rdquo; itself highly suspect, but they recruit runners, not walkers, for the job of marking the extent of the purchase. Further, colonial agents clear a path for the runners in a reconnaissance of the territory beforehand. As a result, the Penn brothers seize 750,000 acres of Lunaape land.
View a depiction of Thomas Penn, one of the Penn brothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-purchase/</guid>
      <description>By the 1730s, William Penn’s sons – Thomas and John – realize that Lunaape land could be used to resolve their great debts. With the help of a co-conspirator, John Logan, they produce an unsigned draft deed from 1686 in which Lunaapeew ostensibly promise to give up as much land as can be covered in a day and a half’s walk westward from the Delaware River in Bucks County.
Passage written in 1851 by Francis Parkman describing the Walking Purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Penn</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</guid>
      <description>In 1682, William Penn lands in the “Delaware Bay” on a ship bearing smallpox pathogens. By then, the land has been designated as William Penn’s by English King Charles II to resolve an enormous debt to Penn’s father. Penn already holds lands in West and East New Jersey. Approximately 1,750 British Quakers now live in West New Jersey.
View a depiction of William Penn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
