<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>renaming on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/renaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in renaming on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/renaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assunpink Trail</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/assunpink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/assunpink/</guid>
      <description>Route 27, Nassau Street in Princeton, is a Lunaape trail called the Assunpink, meaning “rocky, watery place.” European settlers find the trail useful since it connects two rivers—the Raritan and Lenapewihittuck, which Europeans name the Delaware. Over centuries, the Assunpink Trail is New Jersey’s main North-South roadway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Nation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>Group of both Unami and Munsee speakers migrate further west to a settlement near what is today Cape Girardeau, Missouri, at the invitation of the Spanish (Cape Girardeau Delawares later settle in Texas and eventually end up on a reservation with Caddo and Wichita communities in present-day western Oklahoma – recognized today as Delaware Nation).
Princeton Herald passage from August 1963 describing the Delaware move to Oklahoma.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenapewihittuck</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</guid>
      <description>By the early 1600s, Lunaapeew have lived along Lenapewihittuck and its tributaries for millennia. Lenapewihittuck means “rapid stream of the Lunaape.” English settlers name it the “Delaware” after Lord de la Warr III, governor of the Virginia colony. Later, settlers refer to both the Munsee and the Unami Lenape as the “Delaware&amp;quot; – people of Lenapewihittuck.
1963 Princeton Herald article describing the origins of the Lenape.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ohio Migration</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</guid>
      <description>A majority of Munsee and Unami speakers join villages along the Susquehanna, Allegheny, and Ohio rivers (known as Ohio Country) and are referred to collectively as the Delaware. Refugees are obliged to live as protectorates of the Six Nations/Iroquois. The Delawares experience pressure to centralize authority and elect a representative chief, which threatens their clan-based system of shared authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton University</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/princeton-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/princeton-university/</guid>
      <description>In 1896, the College of New Jersey is renamed Princeton University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockbridge</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</guid>
      <description>Some Brotherton Reservation families sell their lands and move to New York State to settle among the Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York (187 miles from Princeton). A few stay behind. The New Jersey Assembly agrees in 1801 to sell the reservation and give profits to remaining tribal members.
Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.Courtesy of&amp;nbsp;Princeton University Library Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verrazano and Hudson</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/europeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/europeans/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapeew encounter Europeans around 1524, when Giovanni de Verrazano, an Italian, explores Lunaapahkiing. In 1609, Lunaapeew encounter Henry Hudson and his Dutch ship the Half Moon. Financed by the Dutch East India Company, Hudson claims lands along Muhheakantuck River (later named the Hudson). He reports meeting Lunaapeew along the west shore.
View a depiction of Hudson&amp;rsquo;s ship, the Half Moon, by S. Hollyer in 1909.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
