<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brotherton on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/brotherton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brotherton on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/brotherton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Refusal and Collapse</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Brotherton Indians release statement of refusal to leave New Jersey after Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York and invite Brotherton’s members to join them. By 1802, however, the 80 remaining residents successfully petition the state legislature for permission to sell their land and use the funds to move to Oneida Lake in New York.
Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse. Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Reservation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</guid>
      <description>Under the terms of the 1758 Treaty of Easton, the first Native reservation in the colonies, the Brotherton Reservation, is established near Medford Lakes, sometimes known as Indian Mills, New Jersey. Brotherton is intended to “accommodate” (or concentrate) Lunaapeew who refuse to leave their land. Missionary David Brainerd is appointed guardian of Lunaapeew now called Brotherton Indians.
1963 Princeton Herald article, by John T. Cunningham, describing the origins of Brotherton Reservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brotherton Pact</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-pact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-pact/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples of Brotherton Reservation sign an agreement to stop leasing or selling reservation lands to white settlers.
Read about the Brotherton Pact from 1780.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
