<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>disease on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/disease/</link>
    <description>Recent content in disease on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Settlements</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</guid>
      <description>Dutch explorers establish trade with Lunaapeew in the early 1610s and then build settlements on both sides of Lenapewihittuck (the Delaware) in the 1620s. Lunaape homelands are increasingly populated with Dutch, Swedish, Finnish, and English settlers. They use Lunaape trails to explore the land and transport resources. They also introduce diseases like smallpox, measles, and influenza that would devastate many Indigenous nations.
Map of New Netherland and Manhattan by Johannes Vingboons in 1639.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Princeton</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nuclear-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nuclear-princeton/</guid>
      <description>Nuclear Princeton is an undergraduate-directed project that reveals the impacts of the nuclear sciences and the management of U.S. national security on Native lands, communities, and beyond. Beginning with the Manhattan Project, it locates the histories of toxic environmental racism and the contemporary technoscientific management of U.S. national security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pres. Edwards</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</guid>
      <description>In 1758 preacher and missionary Jonathan Edwards becomes President of the College of New Jersey. He dies from a fever two months after taking office following a smallpox inoculation.
View a postcard depicting President Edward&amp;rsquo;s grave created by the H.C. Leighton Company between 1890 and 1960.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smallpox Blanket Scheme</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/smallpox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/smallpox/</guid>
      <description>An infamous scheme of biological warfare surrounds the Native attack on Fort Pitt during Pontiac’s Rebellion in June 1763. As tensions intensified in the months prior, the British give two Delaware dignitaries large quantities of food and “two blankets and a handkerchief out of the small pox hospital” in exchange for maintaining their trading relationship and thereby easing pressure on soldiers and civilians in the fort. It is commonly believed that these blankets carried smallpox and that the British intended to spread the disease among Native populations by gifting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Penn</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</guid>
      <description>In 1682, William Penn lands in the “Delaware Bay” on a ship bearing smallpox pathogens. By then, the land has been designated as William Penn’s by English King Charles II to resolve an enormous debt to Penn’s father. Penn already holds lands in West and East New Jersey. Approximately 1,750 British Quakers now live in West New Jersey.
View a depiction of William Penn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
