<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>art and culture on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/art-and-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art and culture on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/art-and-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brainerd&#39;s Otterskin Book</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</guid>
      <description>University President Jonathan Edward&amp;rsquo;s bound beaverskin book is presented to the University Library by Mrs. William Edwards. The Hebrew Lexicon (ca. 1645) with its beaverskin binding is likely the work of Lunaapeew for missionary David Brainerd. David Brainerd was a pioneer missionary among Native peoples after being expelled from Yale for his New Light Presbyterian beliefs and comments about an impious faculty member. He founded Bethel Indian Town (ten miles from Princeton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language &amp; History Symposia</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</guid>
      <description>The inaugural Munsee Language &amp;amp; History Symposium at Princeton in 2021 is the first event to bring “Princeton faculty and students in direct dialogue with members of the Munsee-Delaware Nation.&amp;quot; Language keepers Karen Mosko and Ian McCallum, historian Mark Peters, and a number of Native activists and artists lead discussions of Munsee language, history, and culture. The second symposium in October 2022 commemorates Mosko and Peters who passed away just months earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Delaware Story Evening: NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Delaware Story Evening, or NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories), is an annual event hosted by the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey. During this virtual gathering, Munsee-Delaware Nation community member Ian McCallum shares stories from the community in both the Munsee and English languages. McCallum discusses the background to the stories as well as the active and ongoing interpretation and translation process. Artist Katherine Chupik-Hall shares the artistic approach to illustrating the stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Three Sisters Farm</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Three Sisters Farm is created to rebuild community and well-being among Munsee Ramapough clans after centuries of colonial violence, beginning with the Ramapough massacre in 1644 and continuing through a century of state-sanctioned industrial poisoning. The Turtle Clan, for instance, has lived for 56 years in a federal superfund site. The farm cultivates healthy traditionally grown food for distribution at no cost to the community while also earning a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/museum/</guid>
      <description>The Woodruff Museum of Indian Artifacts is created in Bridgeton, New Jersey (86 miles from Princeton). New Jersey recognizes Bridgeton as a Nanticoke Lunaape hometown in 1982.
Read more about the Bridgeton Public Library Woodruff Museum of Indian Artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAISIP Founded</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</guid>
      <description>The Native American and Indigenous Studies Initiative at Princeton is awarded a Humanities Council grant to Professor Sarah Rivett in 2020 to assemble an interdisciplinary working group of faculty, a number of student groups, and Library and Museum staff whose interests focus on Indigenous peoples. Launched in 2021, NAISIP increases awareness of the cultural traditions and experiences of Indigenous peoples globally, as well as over the course of the University’s history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanticoke Tribal Headquarters</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tribal-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tribal-home/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey officially recognizes the state’s Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape Tribal Nation and its hometown in Bridgeton (86 miles from Princeton; first European settlement in 1686). (After a federal lawsuit on the part of the tribe, the state officially re-recognizes the Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape as a tribe in 2018.) The Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape Tribal Office in Bridgeton has said there are more than 12,000 members of the Lenape Tribe in the surrounding region. Held until 2019, the annual two-day pow-wow hosts members of tribal nations across the United States and received about 10,000 spectators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Filmmaking</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/filmmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/filmmaking/</guid>
      <description>Hopi student Victor Masayesva, Jr. writes a senior thesis on “Hopi Oral Tradition,” despite his resistance to writing in languages other than Hopi. He returns to his community after graduate school (University of Arizona), where he begins to create an award-winning body of work of oral histories, photography, and documentary films. Using these expressive forms, he develops a form of poetic image-making based in Native American philosophies and practices and made in the lands where they originate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging Culture</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</guid>
      <description>Around 1858, Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson graduates from the Princeton Theological Seminary (founded in 1812 by the College of New Jersey and the Presbyterian Church). For the next fifteen years, he works as a missionary for the Choctaw in Indian Territory and then in the American West. In 1877, he begins mission work in Alaska (purchased by the U.S. from Russia in 1867) and Siberia and is collecting cultural objects to ensure Indigenous cultural survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seed Farm</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seed-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seed-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Seed Farm is an interdisciplinary research project that grows rare and culturally-meaningful seeds on a 3.5 acre farm near the campus. The project works with community partners such as the Experimental Farm Network, Munsee Three Sisters Medicinal Farm, and the Ujamaa Cooperative Farming Alliance to ask broad research questions related to ecological and social repair and mutualisms. The farm hosts regular Saturday workdays and other events. The farm plot is nestled amidst the 99-acre Stony Ford property, which is managed and supported by the Department of Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Cultural Collections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</guid>
      <description>Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, a graduate from the Princeton Theological Seminary, begins to donate Native American cultural belongings mostly from Alaska, the Pacific Northwest Coast, and the Southwest to the Princeton Theological Seminary. The collection is supplemented by additional Jackson donations in 1883 and 1885.
In 1886, William Libbey (‘1877) returns from an expedition in Alaska with Yakutat Tlingit material, including materials from a shaman’s grave. In 1882, the collection is transferred to the College of New Jersey, and the Museum of Geology and Archaeology (in what is now the faculty room in Nassau Hall), and subsequently to Guyot Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
