<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ohio Country on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/ohio-country/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ohio Country on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/ohio-country/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1866 Delaware Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</guid>
      <description>Following the Civil War, the Delaware continue to suffer under the pressure of increasing white settlement. The U.S. Government signs a final treaty with the Delaware Tribe, the 1866 Delaware Treaty. The Delaware Council “gives up” their reservation in Kansas and relocates to Indian Territory. Just under 1,000 Delaware remove to the Cherokee Nation at an area equal to 160 acres a person. The Delaware purchase a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River valley (Oklahoma-Kansas today).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of Fallen Timbers</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</guid>
      <description>Battle of Fallen Timbers (in present-day northwestern Ohio): Americans defeat intertribal confederacy of Delaware, Shawnee, and a number of other Indigenous forces. The Delaware in this instance are the Delaware who had remained in Ohio during the American Revolution and who become the Delaware Tribe of Indians. The battle leads to the Greenville Treaty the following year, in which most of Ohio Country would be ceded to the colonial Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Alliances</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/british-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/british-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Most New Jersey Lunaape and Lunaapeew reject the invitation from western Delawares to join them in the Ohio Valley. In the mid-late 1700s, the eve of American Revolutionary War, most Delaware groups are living along Ohio and Allegheny rivers. Pro-British Delawares live in what is today northwestern Ohio, and pro-American Delawares near the frontier city of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concession</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/concession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/concession/</guid>
      <description>Following the deceitful Walking Purchase, Lunaapeew refuse to leave their lands. The Pennsylvania government recruits the Haudenosaunee (later called Iroquois) to persuade Lunaapeew to honor the “purchase” and leave the territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Nation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>Group of both Unami and Munsee speakers migrate further west to a settlement near what is today Cape Girardeau, Missouri, at the invitation of the Spanish (Cape Girardeau Delawares later settle in Texas and eventually end up on a reservation with Caddo and Wichita communities in present-day western Oklahoma – recognized today as Delaware Nation).
Princeton Herald passage from August 1963 describing the Delaware move to Oklahoma.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easton Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</guid>
      <description>During the Seven Years&amp;rsquo; War (1754 to 1763), Lunaapeew who have been forced into the Ohio Country (after the Walking Purchase) ally with the French. British colonial governors introduce the 1758 Treaty of Easton to Lunaapeew and other Native nations. The last of Lunaape land in New Jersey is “ceded” for $1,000 Spanish dollars.
At the signing of the Easton Treaty, the Lunaape representative Teedyuscung makes it clear that the deceit of the Walking Purchase had led Lunaapeew to fight against the British.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding Ends</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/departure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/departure/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes learns the truth about his father’s murder by a white man; Colonel George Morgan leaves for Missouri and recommends to Congress that George Morgan White Eyes continue education elsewhere. George Morgan White Eyes writes a series of petitions to George Washington to have his education funded, but Washington ignores his requests. George Morgan White Eyes eventually relinquishes his efforts and asks for permission to return to Ohio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ohio Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</guid>
      <description>A majority of Munsee and Unami speakers join villages along the Susquehanna, Allegheny, and Ohio rivers (known as Ohio Country) and are referred to collectively as the Delaware. Refugees are obliged to live as protectorates of the Six Nations/Iroquois. The Delawares experience pressure to centralize authority and elect a representative chief, which threatens their clan-based system of shared authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Munsee</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ontario-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ontario-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Following the American Revolution in the late 1700s, some pro-British Munsee groups living in northwestern Ohio during the American Revolution migrate to Munceytown along Thames River (Ontario). They were known previously as the Munsee of the Thames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pontiac’s War</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pontiac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pontiac/</guid>
      <description>Named for Pontiac, an influential Odawa (Ottawa) leader among loosely affiliated groups of warriors from many tribal nations who attempt to force the British out of the regions surrounding the Great Lakes. A number of Lunaapeew are involved along with other Shawnee, Wyandot and Mingo groups from Ohio Country.
View a depiction of Pontiac&amp;rsquo;s War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Revolutionary War Exodus</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/exodus/</guid>
      <description>In the late 1700s, following the American Revolution, Lunaapeew who were considered to be pro-British migrated north and west to Canada and Spanish Territory in order to escape American retaliation. Others stayed within Ohio Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seneca Nation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seneca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seneca/</guid>
      <description>A group of predominantly Munsee settle with the Seneca along the Allegheny River. Today they constitute the assimilated members of the Seneca Nation of Indians located on Allegheny Indian Reservation in southwestern New York.
View a map showing Seneca Nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treaty of Greenville</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</guid>
      <description>In the 1794 Jay Treaty between Britain and the United States, Britain withdraws their association with Native Americans south of Canada, weakening the position of pro-British Native Americans in the United States. Months later, the Delaware and several nations sign the Treaty of Greenville with the colonial Americans. For an annuity of approximately $9,500 they “cede” all but a patch of Ohio land, which the United States retains the right to purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westward Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</guid>
      <description>The Walking Purchase is a key event in the forced migration of southern Lunaape communities westward into Ohio Country, shaping Lunaape/British relations for decades to follow.
A 1765 engraving by Thomas Hutchins showing where American military forces marched in a section of the Ohio River Valley, where native tribes were living.Library of Congress </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
