<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Peters on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/mark-peters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mark Peters on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/mark-peters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorial of Historian Mark Peters</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</guid>
      <description>Mark Peters, Munsee–Delaware Nation member who served his people in many different roles, was a dedicated historian who shared his knowledge within the community and far beyond, both through his travels and through online video lectures. Those at Princeton will long remember his time on Lunaapahkiing, along with his daughter Katelyn, for the inaugural Munsee Language and History Symposium in November 2021. Together with Ian McCallum, he spent time with Lunaape language items and Munsee land documents at Firestone Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Names Project</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-names/</guid>
      <description>Melissa Moreton, Caitlin Rizzo, and Suzanne Conklin Akbari describe the Munsee Names Project as “an Indigenous-led effort to support rediscovery and reclamation of the names of historical Munsee peoples - names and histories that have largely been lost, erased, or presented through the perspective of non-Indigenous peoples across the historical record.” The project began in November 2021 under Mark Peters (historian, knowledge keeper, and member of the Munsee Delaware Nation in Ontario), in collaboration with scholars and archivists at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
