<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cultural property on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/cultural-property/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cultural property on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/cultural-property/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brainerd&#39;s Otterskin Book</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</guid>
      <description>University President Jonathan Edward&amp;rsquo;s bound beaverskin book is presented to the University Library by Mrs. William Edwards. The Hebrew Lexicon (ca. 1645) with its beaverskin binding is likely the work of Lunaapeew for missionary David Brainerd. David Brainerd was a pioneer missionary among Native peoples after being expelled from Yale for his New Light Presbyterian beliefs and comments about an impious faculty member. He founded Bethel Indian Town (ten miles from Princeton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on American Indian Affairs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</guid>
      <description>The Princeton University Library publishes the online collection of the American Indian Affairs records which includes over 240 digitized books and manuscripts, some selected by librarians and others requested by Indigenous researchers. Records include land deeds, missionary-created language dictionaries and translations of religious documents. Graduate students work with librarians to create searchable Munsee dictionaries from the newly-digitized books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on Indigenous Cultures</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</guid>
      <description>The University Library deepens its commitment to Indigenous studies with the newly organized Indigenous Studies Libguide, the Indigenous Cultures online collection, and a digitized collection of Lunaape/Delaware language items.
Browse items related to indigenous cultures and items specific to Lunaapee peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging Culture</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</guid>
      <description>Around 1858, Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson graduates from the Princeton Theological Seminary (founded in 1812 by the College of New Jersey and the Presbyterian Church). For the next fifteen years, he works as a missionary for the Choctaw in Indian Territory and then in the American West. In 1877, he begins mission work in Alaska (purchased by the U.S. from Russia in 1867) and Siberia and is collecting cultural objects to ensure Indigenous cultural survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</guid>
      <description>The Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession Symposium reunites Tlingit scholars and artists with Tlingit belongings held at the Princeton University Art Museum. In the late nineteenth century, Presbyterian missionary Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, Professor William Libbey (class of 1877), and Lieutenant George T. Emmons brought hundreds of Tlingit belongings from southeastern Alaska to the Princeton Theological Seminary. Moving from the Department of Geosciences to the Art of the Ancient Americas, the institutional drift of these Tlingit belongings reflects an ongoing condition of broken knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Cultural Collections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</guid>
      <description>Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, a graduate from the Princeton Theological Seminary, begins to donate Native American cultural belongings mostly from Alaska, the Pacific Northwest Coast, and the Southwest to the Princeton Theological Seminary. The collection is supplemented by additional Jackson donations in 1883 and 1885.
In 1886, William Libbey (‘1877) returns from an expedition in Alaska with Yakutat Tlingit material, including materials from a shaman’s grave. In 1882, the collection is transferred to the College of New Jersey, and the Museum of Geology and Archaeology (in what is now the faculty room in Nassau Hall), and subsequently to Guyot Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
