<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indigenous studies on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/indigenous-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indigenous studies on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/indigenous-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Advocacy Coalition</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/advocacy/</guid>
      <description>The student-organized Indigenous Advocacy Coalition forms within the PACE Center for Civic Engagement as a student group advocating for Native students and expanding Indigenous Studies at Princeton.
Read about Natives at Princeton who are current and alumni student groups who are part of the Indigenous Advocacy Coalition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous/Settler Conference</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</guid>
      <description>“Indigenous/Settler” conference examines methods for thinking across geographies, building alliances, and fighting settler colonialism at large without abandoning attention to specific histories and struggles. Located on the site of Lunaapahkiing—and from the ground of Princeton’s colonial establishment—the conference explores and historicizes what has been called “trans” or “pan” or “global” Indigenous studies.&amp;quot;
See the poster for the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.
Browse photos from the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ivy Native Council</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ivy-natives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ivy-natives/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, Princeton hosts the Ivy Native Council conference, which brings together Indigenous students from all Ivy League universities to exchange ideas and share in fellowship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language &amp; History Symposia</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</guid>
      <description>The inaugural Munsee Language &amp;amp; History Symposium at Princeton in 2021 is the first event to bring “Princeton faculty and students in direct dialogue with members of the Munsee-Delaware Nation.&amp;quot; Language keepers Karen Mosko and Ian McCallum, historian Mark Peters, and a number of Native activists and artists lead discussions of Munsee language, history, and culture. The second symposium in October 2022 commemorates Mosko and Peters who passed away just months earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial of Historian Mark Peters</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</guid>
      <description>Mark Peters, Munsee–Delaware Nation member who served his people in many different roles, was a dedicated historian who shared his knowledge within the community and far beyond, both through his travels and through online video lectures. Those at Princeton will long remember his time on Lunaapahkiing, along with his daughter Katelyn, for the inaugural Munsee Language and History Symposium in November 2021. Together with Ian McCallum, he spent time with Lunaape language items and Munsee land documents at Firestone Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAISIP Founded</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</guid>
      <description>The Native American and Indigenous Studies Initiative at Princeton is awarded a Humanities Council grant to Professor Sarah Rivett in 2020 to assemble an interdisciplinary working group of faculty, a number of student groups, and Library and Museum staff whose interests focus on Indigenous peoples. Launched in 2021, NAISIP increases awareness of the cultural traditions and experiences of Indigenous peoples globally, as well as over the course of the University’s history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Convocation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</guid>
      <description>During the surge of the American Indian Movement in the early 1970s, Princeton hosts the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March. Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Tewa) of Anthropology chairs the event. Considered by some to be the starting point for Native American Studies, a resolution by Native scholars called for an academic discipline that included Indian ways of knowing left out of European-American education.
Princeton prepares to host the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March 1970.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Faculty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</guid>
      <description>Princeton Anthropology Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Ohkay Owingeh Pueblo) publicly supports the American Indian Movement occupation of Wounded Knee. In 1970, Ortiz, chaired the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars, the first of its kind in Native American history. Arriving from the University of Chicago, where he completed his doctorate, Ortiz became a faculty member in 1967. Working with library curator Alfred Bush, he actively recruits undergraduates from the Southwest, many of whom live on reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Library Collection and Space</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</guid>
      <description>A print collection opens on the first floor of Firestone Library focused on Indigenous Studies. The first shelf is a “living land acknowledgement” featuring books related to the Munsee community and relevant campus history. The other shelves feature voices of Indigenous authors. Visitors are encouraged to browse and borrow the books and to suggest additions to the collection, which includes materials from across the world. Natalie Diaz, Pulitzer-prize winning author, meets with Native graduate students in the space which is suitable for small conversational events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
