<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leaves on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leaves on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1866 Delaware Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/1866-delaware-treaty/</guid>
      <description>Following the Civil War, the Delaware continue to suffer under the pressure of increasing white settlement. The U.S. Government signs a final treaty with the Delaware Tribe, the 1866 Delaware Treaty. The Delaware Council “gives up” their reservation in Kansas and relocates to Indian Territory. Just under 1,000 Delaware remove to the Cherokee Nation at an area equal to 160 acres a person. The Delaware purchase a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River valley (Oklahoma-Kansas today).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/religious-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/religious-freedom/</guid>
      <description>Enacted in 1978, the American Indian Religious Freedom Act protects Native Americans&amp;rsquo; freedom to engage in traditional Indigenous religious and cultural practices, many of which the U.S. government had previously banned. The act also protects access and use of sites and sacred objects for such practices.
Read the American Indian Religious Freedom Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assunpink Trail</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</guid>
      <description>Route 27, Nassau Street in Princeton, is a Lunaape trail called the Assunpink, meaning “rocky, watery place.” European settlers find the trail useful since it connects two rivers—the Raritan and Lenapewihittuck, which Europeans name the Delaware. Over centuries, the Assunpink Trail is New Jersey’s main North-South roadway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bartholemew Calvin (Shawukukhkung)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</guid>
      <description>In 1774 Bartholomew Scott Calvin (Shawukukhkung or Wilted Grass) (Lunaape) matriculates at the College of New Jersey. His father is Stephen Calvin, Native translator at the Treaty of Easton. Missionary David Brainerd from nearby Cranbury advocates for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s admission to College President John Witherspoon and Calvin is sponsored by the Scottish Society for the Propagation of Christian Knowledge. Funds are cut off in 1776 during the Revolutionary War, and Calvin has to drop out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of Fallen Timbers</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/fallen-timbers/</guid>
      <description>Battle of Fallen Timbers (in present-day northwestern Ohio): Americans defeat intertribal confederacy of Delaware, Shawnee, and a number of other Indigenous forces. The Delaware in this instance are the Delaware who had remained in Ohio during the American Revolution and who become the Delaware Tribe of Indians. The battle leads to the Greenville Treaty the following year, in which most of Ohio Country would be ceded to the colonial Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethel Mission</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/bethel-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/bethel-mission/</guid>
      <description>In 1746, Presbyterian minister David Brainerd founds Bethel Indian Town, or the Bethel Mission Settlement, comprised of Lunaapeew who have converted to Christianity. Brainerd dies from tuberculosis a year later, but Bethel Mission does not disband until 1759. The Bethel site is about fifteen miles east of Princeton, in what is now Monroe Township. Brainerd is also mentor to Stephen Calvin (Lunaape), a Native translator at the Treaty of Easton; and he advocated for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s son Bartholemew Scott Calvin to matriculate at Princeton in 1774.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainerd&#39;s Otterskin Book</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/beaverskin/</guid>
      <description>University President Jonathan Edward&amp;rsquo;s bound beaverskin book is presented to the University Library by Mrs. William Edwards. The Hebrew Lexicon (ca. 1645) with its beaverskin binding is likely the work of Lunaapeew for missionary David Brainerd. David Brainerd was a pioneer missionary among Native peoples after being expelled from Yale for his New Light Presbyterian beliefs and comments about an impious faculty member. He founded Bethel Indian Town (ten miles from Princeton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Refusal and Collapse</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Brotherton Indians release statement of refusal to leave New Jersey after Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York and invite Brotherton’s members to join them. By 1802, however, the 80 remaining residents successfully petition the state legislature for permission to sell their land and use the funds to move to Oneida Lake in New York.
Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse. Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Reservation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-res/</guid>
      <description>Under the terms of the 1758 Treaty of Easton, the first Native reservation in the colonies, the Brotherton Reservation, is established near Medford Lakes, sometimes known as Indian Mills, New Jersey. Brotherton is intended to “accommodate” (or concentrate) Lunaapeew who refuse to leave their land. Missionary David Brainerd is appointed guardian of Lunaapeew now called Brotherton Indians.
1963 Princeton Herald article, by John T. Cunningham, describing the origins of Brotherton Reservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/land-donated/</guid>
      <description>Thanks mainly to the donation and fund-raising work of Nathaniel FitzRandolph—son of an “original Quaker settler”–Princeton outbids New Brunswick for 1,700 New Jersey pounds in funding, ten acres of “cleared” land for the campus, and 200 acres of woodland for fuel. FitzRandolph alone donates 4.5 acres. There is no recorded consultation between Nathaniel FitzRandolph’s ancestors and the Lunaapeew. Likewise, there is no mention of the Lunaapeew in the documents detailing the enormous “land donation” from the people of Princeton to the College of New Jersey in the mid-1700s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherokee Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cherokee-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cherokee-purchase/</guid>
      <description>Following the Delaware Treaty, the Delaware Tribe purchases a 10-by-30 mile tract of land from the Cherokee Nation situated along the upper Caney River Valley (Kènii Sipu, around the Oklahoma-Kansas border). Delaware chief John Conner writes to Cherokee Chief William P. Ross (1842 Princeton alum) confirming the sale and stating his choice of the “preservation” over “incorporation” option, consistent with the 1866 U.S. Treaty with the Cherokee of 1866. The Delaware Tribe preserves its tribal integrity, vouching to maintain tribal organization in ways not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the Cherokee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheswold, DE</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cheswold-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cheswold-de/</guid>
      <description>﻿Area known as “Cheswold” in Kent County, Delaware (92 miles from Princeton) becomes a village of coalescing Lunaape and Nanticoke families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chief White Eyes</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/white-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/white-eyes/</guid>
      <description>Chief White Eyes (named Koquethagechton) is a principal chief among the Lunaapeew, and a key figure in maintaining tribal neutrality and protecting Native land during the American Revolution. Chief White Eyes is one of the signatories on the 1778 Treaty of Fort Pitt and marries Rachael Doddridge, an assimilated English woman captured in a Lunaape raid at age five. He works closely with and strikes up a friendship with Colonel George Morgan at Fort Pitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiefs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/chiefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/chiefs/</guid>
      <description>British and Iroquois compel Lunaapeew to appoint a single chief for negotiations, violating the established Lunaape system of shared authority among multiple sachems, or chiefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College of NJ Opens</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/college-of-nj-opens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/college-of-nj-opens/</guid>
      <description>In April 1747, the College of New Jersey holds its first classes in the parsonage of first president Jonathan Dickinson in Elizabethtown, New Jersey. Later that year, the College moves to Newark, home of second president, Aaron Burr. Meanwhile, Burr and the trustees seek out a permanent land base for the College.
Charter document for the College of New Jersey.Board of Trustees Records, AC120, Princeton University Archives, Department of Special Collections, Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonel George Morgan</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/col-morgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/col-morgan/</guid>
      <description>Colonel George Morgan is appointed Agent of Indian Affairs by the Continental Congress. Morgan is proprietor of Prospect Farm and future friend of Lunaape Chief White Eyes.
Nassau Literary Magazine clipping on Colonel George Morgan, authored by Raymond Fosdick in 1906.Daily Princetonian Princeton Weekly Bulletin clipping on George Morgan White Eyes, authored by Caroline Moseley in 1992.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Alliances</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/british-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/british-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Most New Jersey Lunaape and Lunaapeew reject the invitation from western Delawares to join them in the Ohio Valley. In the mid-late 1700s, the eve of American Revolutionary War, most Delaware groups are living along Ohio and Allegheny rivers. Pro-British Delawares live in what is today northwestern Ohio, and pro-American Delawares near the frontier city of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concession</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/concession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/concession/</guid>
      <description>Following the deceitful Walking Purchase, Lunaapeew refuse to leave their lands. The Pennsylvania government recruits the Haudenosaunee (later called Iroquois) to persuade Lunaapeew to honor the “purchase” and leave the territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Nation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>Group of both Unami and Munsee speakers migrate further west to a settlement near what is today Cape Girardeau, Missouri, at the invitation of the Spanish (Cape Girardeau Delawares later settle in Texas and eventually end up on a reservation with Caddo and Wichita communities in present-day western Oklahoma – recognized today as Delaware Nation).
Princeton Herald passage from August 1963 describing the Delaware move to Oklahoma.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kevin Gover</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/honorary-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/honorary-degree/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Gover, a citizen of the Pawnee and Comanche Nations, receives Princeton’s first honorary degree conferred upon a Native American. Gover served as Assistant Secretary of the Interior for Indian Affairs under President Bill Clinton and later as director of the National Museum of the American Indian.
2001 photograph by Denise Applewhite of Kevin Gover.Princeton University Library Read a 1975 newspaper article describing Kevin Gover, written by Steve Riegel.
See a photo of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easton Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-treaty-signed/</guid>
      <description>During the Seven Years&amp;rsquo; War (1754 to 1763), Lunaapeew who have been forced into the Ohio Country (after the Walking Purchase) ally with the French. British colonial governors introduce the 1758 Treaty of Easton to Lunaapeew and other Native nations. The last of Lunaape land in New Jersey is “ceded” for $1,000 Spanish dollars.
At the signing of the Easton Treaty, the Lunaape representative Teedyuscung makes it clear that the deceit of the Walking Purchase had led Lunaapeew to fight against the British.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emigration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/emigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/emigration/</guid>
      <description>First Lunaapeew move westward to the hills of Eastern Pennslyvania.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</guid>
      <description>Willim Penn hopes to make a profit from purchasing and selling lands and by collecting taxes. Yet his Quaker values oblige him to treat Lunaapeew equally. He demands of his fellow Quakers that “no man shall … in word or deed, affront or wrong any Indian.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding Ends</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/departure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/departure/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes learns the truth about his father’s murder by a white man; Colonel George Morgan leaves for Missouri and recommends to Congress that George Morgan White Eyes continue education elsewhere. George Morgan White Eyes writes a series of petitions to George Washington to have his education funded, but Washington ignores his requests. George Morgan White Eyes eventually relinquishes his efforts and asks for permission to return to Ohio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Attends</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/matriculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/matriculation/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes matriculates at the College of New Jersey in 1785. Tuition is paid by the Continental Congress resulting in the first instance of “U.S. aid&amp;quot; to education which is designated for three Lunaape students, George Morgan White Eyes and the Killbuck Brothers. This aid is said to be a result of Colonel Morgan’s lobbying following the murder of his friend Chief White Eyes. The Lunaapeew later learn that they are expected to repay the expense with a grant of their land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Stays at Prospect</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/guardian/</guid>
      <description>Son of Chief White Eyes and Rachael Doddridge, George Morgan White Eyes, and his two cousins (the Killbuck brothers) are put in the care of Indian Agent and namesake George Morgan at his Prospect Farm. George Morgan was close friend of the slain Chief White Eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenland Tavern</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</guid>
      <description>In 1683, the Henry Greenland Tavern is established along the Assunpink Trail, equidistant from the settlements of Philadelphia and New York. 1683 is the settlement date declared on the “Welcome to Princeton” signs today. Although the University declares that the “settlement” date is 1696, by then “Princeton” lands have been lived on for millennia by Lunaapeew.
1987 Town Topics article description of Henry Greenland.Princeton University Library View a map of early Stony Brook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/independence/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapeew gain independent tribal status in 1996. Two nations are recognized by New Jersey and one by the state of Delaware. Many unrecognized Lunaape communities remain outside New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Advocacy Coalition</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/advocacy/</guid>
      <description>The student-organized Indigenous Advocacy Coalition forms within the PACE Center for Civic Engagement as a student group advocating for Native students and expanding Indigenous Studies at Princeton.
Read about Natives at Princeton who are current and alumni student groups who are part of the Indigenous Advocacy Coalition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Affinity Space</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/affinity-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/affinity-space/</guid>
      <description>Princeton establishes permanent affinity space for Indigenous students and the Natives at Princeton student organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Language Alliance</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Princeton’s Indigenous Language Alliance is a community for individuals at Princeton and beyond who are learning or would like to learn Indigenous languages and who are interested in language revitalization. Its members hope to support language revitalization efforts among Native communities and increase access to language-learning opportunities for Native students. The alliance includes graduate students, undergraduates, librarians, Princeton faculty and staff, scholars from the Institute for Advanced Study, and language learners from other universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous/Settler Conference</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/conference/</guid>
      <description>“Indigenous/Settler” conference examines methods for thinking across geographies, building alliances, and fighting settler colonialism at large without abandoning attention to specific histories and struggles. Located on the site of Lunaapahkiing—and from the ground of Princeton’s colonial establishment—the conference explores and historicizes what has been called “trans” or “pan” or “global” Indigenous studies.&amp;quot;
See the poster for the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.
Browse photos from the 2019 Indigenous/Settler Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ivy Native Council</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ivy-natives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ivy-natives/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, Princeton hosts the Ivy Native Council conference, which brings together Indigenous students from all Ivy League universities to exchange ideas and share in fellowship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacob Wooley (Lunaape)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/woolley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/woolley/</guid>
      <description>In 1758 Jacob Wooley (Lunaape) matriculates at the College of New Jersey. He is potentially the first Native alumnus but is dismissed during his studies and does not graduate.
Read a letter authored by Jacob Wooley in 1761 (in part) describing his college experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kansas</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kansas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kansas/</guid>
      <description>Delaware Tribe moves from White River, Indiana, to Kansas (junction of Kansas and Missouri rivers).
View a photograph of &amp;ldquo;Delaware Indians&amp;rdquo; between 1860 and 1865.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingston</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</guid>
      <description>In 1709, a Jedediah Higgins “buys” one thousand acres from Lunaapeew next to the Assunpink Trail in an exchange for a sow and piglets. This land becomes the settler town of Kingston, which neighbors Princeton.
1983 Princeton Recollector article describing Jedediah Higgins.Princeton University Library View a photo of Jedediah Higgins House.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language &amp; History Symposia</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/symposia/</guid>
      <description>The inaugural Munsee Language &amp;amp; History Symposium at Princeton in 2021 is the first event to bring “Princeton faculty and students in direct dialogue with members of the Munsee-Delaware Nation.&amp;quot; Language keepers Karen Mosko and Ian McCallum, historian Mark Peters, and a number of Native activists and artists lead discussions of Munsee language, history, and culture. The second symposium in October 2022 commemorates Mosko and Peters who passed away just months earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenapewihittuck</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lenapewihittuck/</guid>
      <description>By the early 1600s, Lunaapeew have lived along Lenapewihittuck and its tributaries for millennia. Lenapewihittuck means “rapid stream of the Lunaape.” English settlers name it the “Delaware” after Lord de la Warr III, governor of the Virginia colony. Later, settlers refer to both the Munsee and the Unami Lenape as the “Delaware&amp;quot; – people of Lenapewihittuck.
1963 Princeton Herald article describing the origins of the Lenape.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunaapahkiing</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/lunaapahkiing/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapahkiing means “lands of the Lenape” in the Munsee (Lunaape) language. It is Lunaape ancestral homeland since time immemorial and includes the unceded grounds of Princeton University.
Delaware-English spelling book by David Zeisberger written in 1776.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunaape Language Camp</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/language-camp/</guid>
      <description>Munsee language teachers organize a Delaware (Lunaape) language camp with Princeton and IAS faculty. The gathering includes teachers from all of the Munsee-speaking nations, along with young adult community members who may become future teachers. The schedule includes traditional land-based learning, including time at the Seed Farm located in Princeton (which is a collaborative partnership with Ramapough Lunaape Nation members), as well as a half-day journey on the Millstone River, sharing Lunaape language, local history, and discussions of Indigenous sovereignty in today’s world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannahatta</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/mannahatta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/mannahatta/</guid>
      <description>In 1624, the Dutch colonize the southern tip of Manhattan Island and establish a trading post, which becomes New Amsterdam, and later, New York City. The fur trade booms. Manhattan, or Mannahatta, is a Munsee Lunaape word for the “bow-gathering place.”
1916 redraft of the Castello Plan, a 1660 map of New Amsterdam. The east-west land barrier (running top-to-bottom on the map) is the border wall after which Wall Street is named.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massacre</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/gnadenhutten-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/gnadenhutten-massacre/</guid>
      <description>Munsee converts from Pennsylvania follow Moravian missionary David Zeisberger to eastern Ohio, where he founds several Native Moravian villages. The British arrest him during the Revolutionary War under suspicion of helping the Patriots. While under arrest at Fort Detroit, nearly one hundred of his Native American followers are murdered in what is memorialized as the Gnadenhutten Massacre. This leads to the Moravian Delaware migration.
Description of the Gnaddenhuetten Massacre written by the Gnadenhuetten Monument Society in 1847.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial of Historian Mark Peters</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</guid>
      <description>Mark Peters, Munsee–Delaware Nation member who served his people in many different roles, was a dedicated historian who shared his knowledge within the community and far beyond, both through his travels and through online video lectures. Those at Princeton will long remember his time on Lunaapahkiing, along with his daughter Katelyn, for the inaugural Munsee Language and History Symposium in November 2021. Together with Ian McCallum, he spent time with Lunaape language items and Munsee land documents at Firestone Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minisink</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/minisink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/minisink/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Lunaapeew live along the Upper Delaware, in a region called Minisink, and along Muhheakantuck, or the “Hudson.” The land that became “Princeton” is likely home to both Munsee and Unami. “Unami” is how the Munsee refer to their relatives in the south, and “Munsee” is how the Unami refer to their relatives in the north.
Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing the Unami.Princeton Recollector Princeton Recollector article from 1985 describing why the Minisink Trail has its name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Delaware Story Evening: NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Delaware Story Evening, or NEEKAAWA KIHTAACHIIMUWAK WULAAKWUNUWII (This Evening They Tell Stories), is an annual event hosted by the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey. During this virtual gathering, Munsee-Delaware Nation community member Ian McCallum shares stories from the community in both the Munsee and English languages. McCallum discusses the background to the stories as well as the active and ongoing interpretation and translation process. Artist Katherine Chupik-Hall shares the artistic approach to illustrating the stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee in Wisconsin</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Small groups of Christian Munsee and Unami converts remaining along the Hudson and Delaware River valleys relocate with Munsee and Mahicans living in Stockbridge, Massachusetts, to a reservation in Wisconsin. They are recognized today as Stockbridge-Munsee Band of Mohican Indians. Among those who moved to Wisconsin was Bartholemew Calvin who matriculated at the College of New Jersey in 1774.
Passage about the Stockbridge Lenape moving to Wisconsin in a Princeton Herald passage written in April 1963 by John Cunningham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Names Project</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-names/</guid>
      <description>Melissa Moreton, Caitlin Rizzo, and Suzanne Conklin Akbari describe the Munsee Names Project as “an Indigenous-led effort to support rediscovery and reclamation of the names of historical Munsee peoples - names and histories that have largely been lost, erased, or presented through the perspective of non-Indigenous peoples across the historical record.” The project began in November 2021 under Mark Peters (historian, knowledge keeper, and member of the Munsee Delaware Nation in Ontario), in collaboration with scholars and archivists at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Three Sisters Farm</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Three Sisters Farm is created to rebuild community and well-being among Munsee Ramapough clans after centuries of colonial violence, beginning with the Ramapough massacre in 1644 and continuing through a century of state-sanctioned industrial poisoning. The Turtle Clan, for instance, has lived for 56 years in a federal superfund site. The farm cultivates healthy traditionally grown food for distribution at no cost to the community while also earning a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/murder/</guid>
      <description>Chief White Eyes is shot and killed by an American militia officer, allegedly out of self-defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/museum/</guid>
      <description>The Woodruff Museum of Indian Artifacts is created in Bridgeton, New Jersey (86 miles from Princeton). New Jersey recognizes Bridgeton as a Nanticoke Lunaape hometown in 1982.
Read more about the Bridgeton Public Library Woodruff Museum of Indian Artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAISIP Founded</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/naisip-founded/</guid>
      <description>The Native American and Indigenous Studies Initiative at Princeton is awarded a Humanities Council grant to Professor Sarah Rivett in 2020 to assemble an interdisciplinary working group of faculty, a number of student groups, and Library and Museum staff whose interests focus on Indigenous peoples. Launched in 2021, NAISIP increases awareness of the cultural traditions and experiences of Indigenous peoples globally, as well as over the course of the University’s history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanticoke Tribal Headquarters</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tribal-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tribal-home/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey officially recognizes the state’s Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape Tribal Nation and its hometown in Bridgeton (86 miles from Princeton; first European settlement in 1686). (After a federal lawsuit on the part of the tribe, the state officially re-recognizes the Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape as a tribe in 2018.) The Nanticoke Lenni-Lenape Tribal Office in Bridgeton has said there are more than 12,000 members of the Lenape Tribe in the surrounding region. Held until 2019, the annual two-day pow-wow hosts members of tribal nations across the United States and received about 10,000 spectators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassau Hall</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nassau-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nassau-hall/</guid>
      <description>In 1756, the construction of Nassau Hall is completed on FitzRandolph’s 4.5 acre donation and the College of New Jersey moves from Newark to Princeton. FitzRandolph proudly records this moment in his journal on November 13 1756: “Aaron Burr, President, preached the first sermon and began the school in Princeton College.” When built, the Nassau was the largest stone buildings in the Colonies and it is most likely where the University&amp;rsquo;s earliest Native students such as Jacob Wooley boarded (in 1759).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Citizenship</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/citizenship/</guid>
      <description>On June 2, 1924, Congress grants citizenship to Native Americans born in the United States. The earlier Fourteenth Amendment (1868), which defines a U.S. citizen as any person born on American soil, did not apply to Indigenous people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Convocation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</guid>
      <description>During the surge of the American Indian Movement in the early 1970s, Princeton hosts the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March. Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Tewa) of Anthropology chairs the event. Considered by some to be the starting point for Native American Studies, a resolution by Native scholars called for an academic discipline that included Indian ways of knowing left out of European-American education.
Princeton prepares to host the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March 1970.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Faculty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/activism/</guid>
      <description>Princeton Anthropology Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Ohkay Owingeh Pueblo) publicly supports the American Indian Movement occupation of Wounded Knee. In 1970, Ortiz, chaired the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars, the first of its kind in Native American history. Arriving from the University of Chicago, where he completed his doctorate, Ortiz became a faculty member in 1967. Working with library curator Alfred Bush, he actively recruits undergraduates from the Southwest, many of whom live on reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Filmmaking</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/filmmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/filmmaking/</guid>
      <description>Hopi student Victor Masayesva, Jr. writes a senior thesis on “Hopi Oral Tradition,” despite his resistance to writing in languages other than Hopi. He returns to his community after graduate school (University of Arizona), where he begins to create an award-winning body of work of oral histories, photography, and documentary films. Using these expressive forms, he develops a form of poetic image-making based in Native American philosophies and practices and made in the lands where they originate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Removal Act</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/removal-act/</guid>
      <description>Under President Andrew Jackson, the Indian Removal Act empowers the U.S. Government with the policy and funds used to “persuade, bribe, and threaten” Indigenous peoples into land-exchange treaties (“removals”) for lands assigned to them in “Indian Territory” west of the Mississippi. See the Indian Removal Act Exhibit.
Native Removal Act from May 28th, 1830.U.S. National Archives </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Students</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recruitment/</guid>
      <description>Twenty-four Native students matriculate at and eventually graduate from Princeton. Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Tewa) from Anthropology along with library curator Alfred Bush and other colleagues work toward recruiting Native Americans &amp;ldquo;so they also can benefit from a Princeton education.&amp;rdquo; Soon after, Native students are awarded funding to support their travel home to participate in events that are key to their advancement into full adulthood.
Seven Native students at Princeton.Princeton Alumni Weekly Read a passage from Town Topics, published in 1975, mentioning 12 Native students at Princeton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Jersey Lawsuit</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/easton-redux/</guid>
      <description>In 1832, Lunaapeew in Wisconsin successfully petition the State of New Jersey for compensation based on claims to lost fishing and hunting rights promised by the 1758 Treaty of Easton. Bartholomew Calvin, who had moved to Wisconsin in 1823, serves as attorney for Lunaapeew and at age 76 appears before the New Jersey state legislature.
Read about Calvin&amp;rsquo;s speech to the New Jersey legislature in 1932.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Jersey Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-purchase/</guid>
      <description>In 1677, Quakers “purchase” all Lunaape land from Sassackon (Timber Creek) to Rancocas Creek, between the Atlantic Ocean and the Delaware River. The deal is made with Chief Katemus Sekappio. Payment is in the form of thirty guns, thirty axes, thirty hoes, thirty jewsharps, one hundred fishhooks, brandy, and other trinkets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Settlements</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</guid>
      <description>Dutch explorers establish trade with Lunaapeew in the early 1610s and then build settlements on both sides of Lenapewihittuck (the Delaware) in the 1620s. Lunaape homelands are increasingly populated with Dutch, Swedish, Finnish, and English settlers. They use Lunaape trails to explore the land and transport resources. They also introduce diseases like smallpox, measles, and influenza that would devastate many Indigenous nations.
Map of New Netherland and Manhattan by Johannes Vingboons in 1639.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NJ Nanticoke</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-nanticoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nj-nanticoke/</guid>
      <description>Nanticoke live along the Delaware River and unite with the Lunaapeew in New Jersey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Princeton</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nuclear-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nuclear-princeton/</guid>
      <description>Nuclear Princeton is an undergraduate-directed project that reveals the impacts of the nuclear sciences and the management of U.S. national security on Native lands, communities, and beyond. Beginning with the Manhattan Project, it locates the histories of toxic environmental racism and the contemporary technoscientific management of U.S. national security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ohio Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/midwest-resettlement/</guid>
      <description>A majority of Munsee and Unami speakers join villages along the Susquehanna, Allegheny, and Ohio rivers (known as Ohio Country) and are referred to collectively as the Delaware. Refugees are obliged to live as protectorates of the Six Nations/Iroquois. The Delawares experience pressure to centralize authority and elect a representative chief, which threatens their clan-based system of shared authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on American Indian Affairs</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/archives/</guid>
      <description>The Princeton University Library publishes the online collection of the American Indian Affairs records which includes over 240 digitized books and manuscripts, some selected by librarians and others requested by Indigenous researchers. Records include land deeds, missionary-created language dictionaries and translations of religious documents. Graduate students work with librarians to create searchable Munsee dictionaries from the newly-digitized books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on Indigenous Cultures</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</guid>
      <description>The University Library deepens its commitment to Indigenous studies with the newly organized Indigenous Studies Libguide, the Indigenous Cultures online collection, and a digitized collection of Lunaape/Delaware language items.
Browse items related to indigenous cultures and items specific to Lunaapee peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Munsee</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ontario-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ontario-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Following the American Revolution in the late 1700s, some pro-British Munsee groups living in northwestern Ohio during the American Revolution migrate to Munceytown along Thames River (Ontario). They were known previously as the Munsee of the Thames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pontiac’s War</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pontiac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pontiac/</guid>
      <description>Named for Pontiac, an influential Odawa (Ottawa) leader among loosely affiliated groups of warriors from many tribal nations who attempt to force the British out of the regions surrounding the Great Lakes. A number of Lunaapeew are involved along with other Shawnee, Wyandot and Mingo groups from Ohio Country.
View a depiction of Pontiac&amp;rsquo;s War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Revolutionary War Exodus</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/exodus/</guid>
      <description>In the late 1700s, following the American Revolution, Lunaapeew who were considered to be pro-British migrated north and west to Canada and Spanish Territory in order to escape American retaliation. Others stayed within Ohio Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pres. Edwards</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</guid>
      <description>In 1758 preacher and missionary Jonathan Edwards becomes President of the College of New Jersey. He dies from a fever two months after taking office following a smallpox inoculation.
View a postcard depicting President Edward&amp;rsquo;s grave created by the H.C. Leighton Company between 1890 and 1960.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princeton University</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-university/</guid>
      <description>In 1896, the College of New Jersey is renamed Princeton University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Library Collection and Space</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-recognitions/</guid>
      <description>A print collection opens on the first floor of Firestone Library focused on Indigenous Studies. The first shelf is a “living land acknowledgement” featuring books related to the Munsee community and relevant campus history. The other shelves feature voices of Indigenous authors. Visitors are encouraged to browse and borrow the books and to suggest additions to the collection, which includes materials from across the world. Natalie Diaz, Pulitzer-prize winning author, meets with Native graduate students in the space which is suitable for small conversational events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro-British Lunaapeew</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pro-british-lunaapeew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pro-british-lunaapeew/</guid>
      <description>Following the American Revolution, pro-British Lunaapeew migrate north and west to Canada and Spanish Territory in order to escape American retaliation; a few Northern Unami bands join the Iroquois on Six Nations Reserve along Grand River.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospect Occupation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/occupation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/occupation/</guid>
      <description>Following the murder of Chief White Eyes, a delegation of ten Ohio Delaware leaders and their respective retinues assembles at Prospect Farm to assure the U.S. Government of continued loyalty and friendship. Read more about Prospect Farm at Princeton &amp;amp; Slavery.
Read a 1931 description of the 10 Delaware members who came to Prospect during Colonel George Morgan&amp;rsquo;s tenure of the farm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramapough Lenaapeew</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ramapough-lenape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/ramapough-lenape/</guid>
      <description>Munsee-speaking clans live in communities on ancestral lands across the northeast New Jersey-New York border. Nearby Dutch from New Amsterdam attack and kill approximately 700 Native people in what becomes known as the Pound Ridge Massacre in effort to force out these communities.
Visit the Ramapough Culture and Land Foundation website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition of Ritual Authority</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recognition-of-ritual-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recognition-of-ritual-authority/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey recognizes the authority of traditional tribal spiritual leaders to solemnize matrimony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regis Pecos (Cochiti) is first Native American Trustee</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/trustee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/trustee/</guid>
      <description>In 1970 Regis Pecos (Cochiti Pueblo) graduates from Princeton. He later becomes the first Native American to serve as a Princeton trustee in 1997.
1997 Princeton Weekly Bulletin Article describing Regis Pecos.Princeton University Library Read a 2019 story featuring Regis Pecos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging Culture</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</guid>
      <description>Around 1858, Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson graduates from the Princeton Theological Seminary (founded in 1812 by the College of New Jersey and the Presbyterian Church). For the next fifteen years, he works as a missionary for the Choctaw in Indian Territory and then in the American West. In 1877, he begins mission work in Alaska (purchased by the U.S. from Russia in 1867) and Siberia and is collecting cultural objects to ensure Indigenous cultural survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Hill Indians of Monmouth County</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/sand-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/sand-hill/</guid>
      <description>The history of the Sand Hill Indians who live on the northern shores of Monmouth County, New Jersey, can be traced back to the eighteenth century. Lunaape communities had lived in the area for centuries, when a Cherokee family named the Richardsons left their Georgia homelands in the late eighteenth century for New York and New Jersey to live alongside their Lunaape cousins, the Reveys. After living in Eatontown, New Jersey, for over thirty years, Isaac and Elizabeth Richardson move their family to Asbury Park in 1877.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seneca Nation</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seneca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seneca/</guid>
      <description>A group of predominantly Munsee settle with the Seneca along the Allegheny River. Today they constitute the assimilated members of the Seneca Nation of Indians located on Allegheny Indian Reservation in southwestern New York.
View a map showing Seneca Nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smallpox Blanket Scheme</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/smallpox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/smallpox/</guid>
      <description>An infamous scheme of biological warfare surrounds the Native attack on Fort Pitt during Pontiac’s Rebellion in June 1763. As tensions intensified in the months prior, the British give two Delaware dignitaries large quantities of food and “two blankets and a handkerchief out of the small pox hospital” in exchange for maintaining their trading relationship and thereby easing pressure on soldiers and civilians in the fort. It is commonly believed that these blankets carried smallpox and that the British intended to spread the disease among Native populations by gifting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockbridge</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/stockbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/stockbridge/</guid>
      <description>Some Brotherton Reservation families sell their lands and move to New York State to settle among the Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York (187 miles from Princeton). A few stay behind. The New Jersey Assembly agrees in 1801 to sell the reservation and give profits to remaining tribal members.
Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.Courtesy of&amp;nbsp;Princeton University Library Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brotherton Pact</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-pact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-pact/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples of Brotherton Reservation sign an agreement to stop leasing or selling reservation lands to white settlers.
Read about the Brotherton Pact from 1780.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dutch in Princeton</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-princeton/</guid>
      <description>In 1737, the Penn brothers sell Princeton area land to Dutch farmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seed Farm</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seed-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/seed-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Seed Farm is an interdisciplinary research project that grows rare and culturally-meaningful seeds on a 3.5 acre farm near the campus. The project works with community partners such as the Experimental Farm Network, Munsee Three Sisters Medicinal Farm, and the Ujamaa Cooperative Farming Alliance to ask broad research questions related to ecological and social repair and mutualisms. The farm hosts regular Saturday workdays and other events. The farm plot is nestled amidst the 99-acre Stony Ford property, which is managed and supported by the Department of Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shackamaxon Treaty</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/shackamaxon-treaty/</guid>
      <description>According to legend, William Penn enters into a treaty with Lunaapeew in 1682. The Treaty of Shackamaxon is signed under an elm tree in a sacred Lunaape area known as Shackamaxon, which is north of Philadelphia and along the Lenapewihittuck/Delaware River. Penn signs agreements with Lunaapeew that bring lands deeded to him under his absolute title, while still recognizing and reserving certain lands for Lunaapeew where their villages are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Yong</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/yong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/yong/</guid>
      <description>In 1634, Lunaapeew encounter the English captain, Thomas Yong, in the area now called Princeton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/tlingit-art/</guid>
      <description>The Tlingit Art, Spirit, and Ancestry: Healing Histories of Dispossession Symposium reunites Tlingit scholars and artists with Tlingit belongings held at the Princeton University Art Museum. In the late nineteenth century, Presbyterian missionary Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, Professor William Libbey (class of 1877), and Lieutenant George T. Emmons brought hundreds of Tlingit belongings from southeastern Alaska to the Princeton Theological Seminary. Moving from the Department of Geosciences to the Art of the Ancient Americas, the institutional drift of these Tlingit belongings reflects an ongoing condition of broken knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treaty of Greenville</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/greenville-treaty/</guid>
      <description>In the 1794 Jay Treaty between Britain and the United States, Britain withdraws their association with Native Americans south of Canada, weakening the position of pro-British Native Americans in the United States. Months later, the Delaware and several nations sign the Treaty of Greenville with the colonial Americans. For an annuity of approximately $9,500 they “cede” all but a patch of Ohio land, which the United States retains the right to purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unami Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/unami-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/unami-migration/</guid>
      <description>Southern New Jersey Lënape migrate to Pennsylvania with the Nanticokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Cultural Collections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-property/</guid>
      <description>Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson, a graduate from the Princeton Theological Seminary, begins to donate Native American cultural belongings mostly from Alaska, the Pacific Northwest Coast, and the Southwest to the Princeton Theological Seminary. The collection is supplemented by additional Jackson donations in 1883 and 1885.
In 1886, William Libbey (‘1877) returns from an expedition in Alaska with Yakutat Tlingit material, including materials from a shaman’s grave. In 1882, the collection is transferred to the College of New Jersey, and the Museum of Geology and Archaeology (in what is now the faculty room in Nassau Hall), and subsequently to Guyot Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verrazano and Hudson</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/europeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/europeans/</guid>
      <description>Lunaapeew encounter Europeans around 1524, when Giovanni de Verrazano, an Italian, explores Lunaapahkiing. In 1609, Lunaapeew encounter Henry Hudson and his Dutch ship the Half Moon. Financed by the Dutch East India Company, Hudson claims lands along Muhheakantuck River (later named the Hudson). He reports meeting Lunaapeew along the west shore.
View a depiction of Hudson&amp;rsquo;s ship, the Half Moon, by S. Hollyer in 1909.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Deceit</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-deceit/</guid>
      <description>Not only is Thomas and John Penns&amp;rsquo; deed underlying the &amp;ldquo;Walking Purchase&amp;rdquo; itself highly suspect, but they recruit runners, not walkers, for the job of marking the extent of the purchase. Further, colonial agents clear a path for the runners in a reconnaissance of the territory beforehand. As a result, the Penn brothers seize 750,000 acres of Lunaape land.
View a depiction of Thomas Penn, one of the Penn brothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Purchase</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-purchase/</guid>
      <description>By the 1730s, William Penn’s sons – Thomas and John – realize that Lunaape land could be used to resolve their great debts. With the help of a co-conspirator, John Logan, they produce an unsigned draft deed from 1686 in which Lunaapeew ostensibly promise to give up as much land as can be covered in a day and a half’s walk westward from the Delaware River in Bucks County.
Passage written in 1851 by Francis Parkman describing the Walking Purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Suit</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-lawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/walking-lawsuit/</guid>
      <description>In 2006, Lunaapeew seek redress for the fraudulent Walking Purchase, but the U.S. Tenth Circuit Court of Appeals rules that the claim, although substantive, is “nonjusticiable.”
Read the case text of lawsuit filed due to Walking Purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Westward Migration</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/westward-migration/</guid>
      <description>The Walking Purchase is a key event in the forced migration of southern Lunaape communities westward into Ohio Country, shaping Lunaape/British relations for decades to follow.
A 1765 engraving by Thomas Hutchins showing where American military forces marched in a section of the Ohio River Valley, where native tribes were living.Library of Congress </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Penn</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wm-penn/</guid>
      <description>In 1682, William Penn lands in the “Delaware Bay” on a ship bearing smallpox pathogens. By then, the land has been designated as William Penn’s by English King Charles II to resolve an enormous debt to Penn’s father. Penn already holds lands in West and East New Jersey. Approximately 1,750 British Quakers now live in West New Jersey.
View a depiction of William Penn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Potter Ross</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/william-potter-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/william-potter-ross/</guid>
      <description>William Potter Ross graduates from the College of New Jersey first in his class around 1842. His uncle and prominent Cherokee statesman Chief John Ross funded William&amp;rsquo;s education. William is a slave-holder who defends the generous treatment of slaves and serves as a Confederate officer and diplomat during the Civil War. He is elected to succeed his uncle as Principal Chief of the Cherokee Nation in 1866, after the Civil War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witherspoon’s Reflections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/witherspoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/witherspoon/</guid>
      <description>As the sixth president of the College of New Jersey, John Witherspoon reflects on “experiment” of educating Native Americans: “On the whole it does not appear, that either by our people going among them, or by their being brought among us, that it is possible to give them a relish of civilized life. There have been some of them educated at this college, as well as in New England; but seldom if never did they ever prove good or useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
