<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>colonial governments on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/colonial-governments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in colonial governments on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/colonial-governments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Colonel George Morgan</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</guid>
      <description>Colonel George Morgan is appointed Agent of Indian Affairs by the Continental Congress. Morgan is proprietor of Prospect Farm and future friend of Lunaape Chief White Eyes.
Nassau Literary Magazine clipping on Colonel George Morgan, authored by Raymond Fosdick in 1906.Daily Princetonian Princeton Weekly Bulletin clipping on George Morgan White Eyes, authored by Caroline Moseley in 1992.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concession</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/concession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/concession/</guid>
      <description>Following the deceitful Walking Purchase, Lunaapeew refuse to leave their lands. The Pennsylvania government recruits the Haudenosaunee (later called Iroquois) to persuade Lunaapeew to honor the “purchase” and leave the territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Valley Properties</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-valley/</guid>
      <description>William Penn and others divide up Native ancestral lands across the Delaware Valley into their own separate colonies and property holdings. For the Unami Lënape, the Delaware River, or Lenapewihittuck, is the unifying center of their territory. But it becomes, for settlers, the dividing line between the New Jersey and Pennsylvania colonies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Attends</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/matriculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/matriculation/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes matriculates at the College of New Jersey in 1785. Tuition is paid by the Continental Congress resulting in the first instance of “U.S. aid&amp;quot; to education which is designated for three Lunaape students, George Morgan White Eyes and the Killbuck Brothers. This aid is said to be a result of Colonel Morgan’s lobbying following the murder of his friend Chief White Eyes. The Lunaapeew later learn that they are expected to repay the expense with a grant of their land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospect Occupation</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/occupation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/occupation/</guid>
      <description>Following the murder of Chief White Eyes, a delegation of ten Ohio Delaware leaders and their respective retinues assembles at Prospect Farm to assure the U.S. Government of continued loyalty and friendship. Read more about Prospect Farm at Princeton &amp;amp; Slavery.
Read a 1931 description of the 10 Delaware members who came to Prospect during Colonel George Morgan&amp;rsquo;s tenure of the farm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockbridge</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</guid>
      <description>Some Brotherton Reservation families sell their lands and move to New York State to settle among the Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York (187 miles from Princeton). A few stay behind. The New Jersey Assembly agrees in 1801 to sell the reservation and give profits to remaining tribal members.
Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.Courtesy of&amp;nbsp;Princeton University Library Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
