<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>religion on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in religion on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/religious-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/religious-freedom/</guid>
      <description>Enacted in 1978, the American Indian Religious Freedom Act protects Native Americans&amp;rsquo; freedom to engage in traditional Indigenous religious and cultural practices, many of which the U.S. government had previously banned. The act also protects access and use of sites and sacred objects for such practices.
Read the American Indian Religious Freedom Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bartholemew Calvin (Shawukukhkung)</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/b-calvin/</guid>
      <description>In 1774 Bartholomew Scott Calvin (Shawukukhkung or Wilted Grass) (Lunaape) matriculates at the College of New Jersey. His father is Stephen Calvin, Native translator at the Treaty of Easton. Missionary David Brainerd from nearby Cranbury advocates for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s admission to College President John Witherspoon and Calvin is sponsored by the Scottish Society for the Propagation of Christian Knowledge. Funds are cut off in 1776 during the Revolutionary War, and Calvin has to drop out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethel Mission</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/bethel-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/bethel-mission/</guid>
      <description>In 1746, Presbyterian minister David Brainerd founds Bethel Indian Town, or the Bethel Mission Settlement, comprised of Lunaapeew who have converted to Christianity. Brainerd dies from tuberculosis a year later, but Bethel Mission does not disband until 1759. The Bethel site is about fifteen miles east of Princeton, in what is now Monroe Township. Brainerd is also mentor to Stephen Calvin (Lunaape), a Native translator at the Treaty of Easton; and he advocated for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s son Bartholemew Scott Calvin to matriculate at Princeton in 1774.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College of NJ Opens</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/college-of-nj-opens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/college-of-nj-opens/</guid>
      <description>In April 1747, the College of New Jersey holds its first classes in the parsonage of first president Jonathan Dickinson in Elizabethtown, New Jersey. Later that year, the College moves to Newark, home of second president, Aaron Burr. Meanwhile, Burr and the trustees seek out a permanent land base for the College.
Charter document for the College of New Jersey.Board of Trustees Records, AC120, Princeton University Archives, Department of Special Collections, Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/equality/</guid>
      <description>Willim Penn hopes to make a profit from purchasing and selling lands and by collecting taxes. Yet his Quaker values oblige him to treat Lunaapeew equally. He demands of his fellow Quakers that “no man shall … in word or deed, affront or wrong any Indian.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee in Wisconsin</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/wisconsin-munsee/</guid>
      <description>Small groups of Christian Munsee and Unami converts remaining along the Hudson and Delaware River valleys relocate with Munsee and Mahicans living in Stockbridge, Massachusetts, to a reservation in Wisconsin. They are recognized today as Stockbridge-Munsee Band of Mohican Indians. Among those who moved to Wisconsin was Bartholemew Calvin who matriculated at the College of New Jersey in 1774.
Passage about the Stockbridge Lenape moving to Wisconsin in a Princeton Herald passage written in April 1963 by John Cunningham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassau Hall</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nassau-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/nassau-hall/</guid>
      <description>In 1756, the construction of Nassau Hall is completed on FitzRandolph’s 4.5 acre donation and the College of New Jersey moves from Newark to Princeton. FitzRandolph proudly records this moment in his journal on November 13 1756: “Aaron Burr, President, preached the first sermon and began the school in Princeton College.” When built, the Nassau was the largest stone buildings in the Colonies and it is most likely where the University&amp;rsquo;s earliest Native students such as Jacob Wooley boarded (in 1759).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Library Collection on Indigenous Cultures</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/library-collections/</guid>
      <description>The University Library deepens its commitment to Indigenous studies with the newly organized Indigenous Studies Libguide, the Indigenous Cultures online collection, and a digitized collection of Lunaape/Delaware language items.
Browse items related to indigenous cultures and items specific to Lunaapee peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pres. Edwards</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/pres-edwards/</guid>
      <description>In 1758 preacher and missionary Jonathan Edwards becomes President of the College of New Jersey. He dies from a fever two months after taking office following a smallpox inoculation.
View a postcard depicting President Edward&amp;rsquo;s grave created by the H.C. Leighton Company between 1890 and 1960.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognition of Ritual Authority</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recognition-of-ritual-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/recognition-of-ritual-authority/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey recognizes the authority of traditional tribal spiritual leaders to solemnize matrimony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging Culture</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/cultural-salvage/</guid>
      <description>Around 1858, Presbyterian Reverend Dr. Sheldon Jackson graduates from the Princeton Theological Seminary (founded in 1812 by the College of New Jersey and the Presbyterian Church). For the next fifteen years, he works as a missionary for the Choctaw in Indian Territory and then in the American West. In 1877, he begins mission work in Alaska (purchased by the U.S. from Russia in 1867) and Siberia and is collecting cultural objects to ensure Indigenous cultural survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witherspoon’s Reflections</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/witherspoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/witherspoon/</guid>
      <description>As the sixth president of the College of New Jersey, John Witherspoon reflects on “experiment” of educating Native Americans: “On the whole it does not appear, that either by our people going among them, or by their being brought among us, that it is possible to give them a relish of civilized life. There have been some of them educated at this college, as well as in New England; but seldom if never did they ever prove good or useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
