<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emigration on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/emigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emigration on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/emigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delaware Nation in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/delaware-nation-in-oklahoma/</guid>
      <description>Group of both Unami and Munsee speakers migrate further west to a settlement near what is today Cape Girardeau, Missouri, at the invitation of the Spanish (Cape Girardeau Delawares later settle in Texas and eventually end up on a reservation with Caddo and Wichita communities in present-day western Oklahoma – recognized today as Delaware Nation).
Princeton Herald passage from August 1963 describing the Delaware move to Oklahoma.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emigration</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/emigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/emigration/</guid>
      <description>First Lunaapeew move westward to the hills of Eastern Pennslyvania.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massacre</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/gnadenhutten-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/gnadenhutten-massacre/</guid>
      <description>Munsee converts from Pennsylvania follow Moravian missionary David Zeisberger to eastern Ohio, where he founds several Native Moravian villages. The British arrest him during the Revolutionary War under suspicion of helping the Patriots. While under arrest at Fort Detroit, nearly one hundred of his Native American followers are murdered in what is memorialized as the Gnadenhutten Massacre. This leads to the Moravian Delaware migration.
Description of the Gnaddenhuetten Massacre written by the Gnadenhuetten Monument Society in 1847.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Revolutionary War Exodus</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/exodus/</guid>
      <description>In the late 1700s, following the American Revolution, Lunaapeew who were considered to be pro-British migrated north and west to Canada and Spanish Territory in order to escape American retaliation. Others stayed within Ohio Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro-British Lunaapeew</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/pro-british-lunaapeew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/pro-british-lunaapeew/</guid>
      <description>Following the American Revolution, pro-British Lunaapeew migrate north and west to Canada and Spanish Territory in order to escape American retaliation; a few Northern Unami bands join the Iroquois on Six Nations Reserve along Grand River.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Hill Indians of Monmouth County</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/sand-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/sand-hill/</guid>
      <description>The history of the Sand Hill Indians who live on the northern shores of Monmouth County, New Jersey, can be traced back to the eighteenth century. Lunaape communities had lived in the area for centuries, when a Cherokee family named the Richardsons left their Georgia homelands in the late eighteenth century for New York and New Jersey to live alongside their Lunaape cousins, the Reveys. After living in Eatontown, New Jersey, for over thirty years, Isaac and Elizabeth Richardson move their family to Asbury Park in 1877.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockbridge</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/stockbridge/</guid>
      <description>Some Brotherton Reservation families sell their lands and move to New York State to settle among the Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York (187 miles from Princeton). A few stay behind. The New Jersey Assembly agrees in 1801 to sell the reservation and give profits to remaining tribal members.
Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.Courtesy of&amp;nbsp;Princeton University Library Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treaty of Greenville</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/greenville-treaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/greenville-treaty/</guid>
      <description>In the 1794 Jay Treaty between Britain and the United States, Britain withdraws their association with Native Americans south of Canada, weakening the position of pro-British Native Americans in the United States. Months later, the Delaware and several nations sign the Treaty of Greenville with the colonial Americans. For an annuity of approximately $9,500 they “cede” all but a patch of Ohio land, which the United States retains the right to purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
