<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>routes on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/routes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in routes on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/routes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assunpink Trail</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/assunpink/</guid>
      <description>Route 27, Nassau Street in Princeton, is a Lunaape trail called the Assunpink, meaning “rocky, watery place.” European settlers find the trail useful since it connects two rivers—the Raritan and Lenapewihittuck, which Europeans name the Delaware. Over centuries, the Assunpink Trail is New Jersey’s main North-South roadway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenland Tavern</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/princeton-settlement/</guid>
      <description>In 1683, the Henry Greenland Tavern is established along the Assunpink Trail, equidistant from the settlements of Philadelphia and New York. 1683 is the settlement date declared on the “Welcome to Princeton” signs today. Although the University declares that the “settlement” date is 1696, by then “Princeton” lands have been lived on for millennia by Lunaapeew.
1987 Town Topics article description of Henry Greenland.Princeton University Library View a map of early Stony Brook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingston</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/kingston/</guid>
      <description>In 1709, a Jedediah Higgins “buys” one thousand acres from Lunaapeew next to the Assunpink Trail in an exchange for a sow and piglets. This land becomes the settler town of Kingston, which neighbors Princeton.
1983 Princeton Recollector article describing Jedediah Higgins.Princeton University Library View a photo of Jedediah Higgins House.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Settlements</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/dutch-settle/</guid>
      <description>Dutch explorers establish trade with Lunaapeew in the early 1610s and then build settlements on both sides of Lenapewihittuck (the Delaware) in the 1620s. Lunaape homelands are increasingly populated with Dutch, Swedish, Finnish, and English settlers. They use Lunaape trails to explore the land and transport resources. They also introduce diseases like smallpox, measles, and influenza that would devastate many Indigenous nations.
Map of New Netherland and Manhattan by Johannes Vingboons in 1639.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
