<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Brainerd on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/david-brainerd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David Brainerd on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/david-brainerd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bartholemew Calvin (Shawukukhkung)</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/b-calvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/b-calvin/</guid>
      <description>In 1774 Bartholomew Scott Calvin (Shawukukhkung or Wilted Grass) (Lunaape) matriculates at the College of New Jersey. His father is Stephen Calvin, Native translator at the Treaty of Easton. Missionary David Brainerd from nearby Cranbury advocates for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s admission to College President John Witherspoon and Calvin is sponsored by the Scottish Society for the Propagation of Christian Knowledge. Funds are cut off in 1776 during the Revolutionary War, and Calvin has to drop out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethel Mission</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/bethel-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/bethel-mission/</guid>
      <description>In 1746, Presbyterian minister David Brainerd founds Bethel Indian Town, or the Bethel Mission Settlement, comprised of Lunaapeew who have converted to Christianity. Brainerd dies from tuberculosis a year later, but Bethel Mission does not disband until 1759. The Bethel site is about fifteen miles east of Princeton, in what is now Monroe Township. Brainerd is also mentor to Stephen Calvin (Lunaape), a Native translator at the Treaty of Easton; and he advocated for Stephen&amp;rsquo;s son Bartholemew Scott Calvin to matriculate at Princeton in 1774.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainerd&#39;s Otterskin Book</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/beaverskin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/beaverskin/</guid>
      <description>University President Jonathan Edward&amp;rsquo;s bound beaverskin book is presented to the University Library by Mrs. William Edwards. The Hebrew Lexicon (ca. 1645) with its beaverskin binding is likely the work of Lunaapeew for missionary David Brainerd. David Brainerd was a pioneer missionary among Native peoples after being expelled from Yale for his New Light Presbyterian beliefs and comments about an impious faculty member. He founded Bethel Indian Town (ten miles from Princeton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Reservation</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/brotherton-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/brotherton-res/</guid>
      <description>Under the terms of the 1758 Treaty of Easton, the first Native reservation in the colonies, the Brotherton Reservation, is established near Medford Lakes, sometimes known as Indian Mills, New Jersey. Brotherton is intended to “accommodate” (or concentrate) Lunaapeew who refuse to leave their land. Missionary David Brainerd is appointed guardian of Lunaapeew now called Brotherton Indians.
1963 Princeton Herald article, by John T. Cunningham, describing the origins of Brotherton Reservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
