<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colonel George Morgan on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/colonel-george-morgan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colonel George Morgan on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/colonel-george-morgan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Colonel George Morgan</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/col-morgan/</guid>
      <description>Colonel George Morgan is appointed Agent of Indian Affairs by the Continental Congress. Morgan is proprietor of Prospect Farm and future friend of Lunaape Chief White Eyes.
Nassau Literary Magazine clipping on Colonel George Morgan, authored by Raymond Fosdick in 1906.Daily Princetonian Princeton Weekly Bulletin clipping on George Morgan White Eyes, authored by Caroline Moseley in 1992.Princeton University Library </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding Ends</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/departure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/departure/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes learns the truth about his father’s murder by a white man; Colonel George Morgan leaves for Missouri and recommends to Congress that George Morgan White Eyes continue education elsewhere. George Morgan White Eyes writes a series of petitions to George Washington to have his education funded, but Washington ignores his requests. George Morgan White Eyes eventually relinquishes his efforts and asks for permission to return to Ohio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Attends</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/matriculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/matriculation/</guid>
      <description>George Morgan White Eyes matriculates at the College of New Jersey in 1785. Tuition is paid by the Continental Congress resulting in the first instance of “U.S. aid&amp;quot; to education which is designated for three Lunaape students, George Morgan White Eyes and the Killbuck Brothers. This aid is said to be a result of Colonel Morgan’s lobbying following the murder of his friend Chief White Eyes. The Lunaapeew later learn that they are expected to repay the expense with a grant of their land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Morgan White Eyes Stays at Prospect</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/guardian/</guid>
      <description>Son of Chief White Eyes and Rachael Doddridge, George Morgan White Eyes, and his two cousins (the Killbuck brothers) are put in the care of Indian Agent and namesake George Morgan at his Prospect Farm. George Morgan was close friend of the slain Chief White Eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
