<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>activism on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/activism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in activism on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/tags/activism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Refusal and Collapse</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Brotherton Indians release statement of refusal to leave New Jersey after Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York and invite Brotherton’s members to join them. By 1802, however, the 80 remaining residents successfully petition the state legislature for permission to sell their land and use the funds to move to Oneida Lake in New York.
Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse. Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concession</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/concession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/concession/</guid>
      <description>Following the deceitful Walking Purchase, Lunaapeew refuse to leave their lands. The Pennsylvania government recruits the Haudenosaunee (later called Iroquois) to persuade Lunaapeew to honor the “purchase” and leave the territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorial of Historian Mark Peters</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/historian-mark-peters/</guid>
      <description>Mark Peters, Munsee–Delaware Nation member who served his people in many different roles, was a dedicated historian who shared his knowledge within the community and far beyond, both through his travels and through online video lectures. Those at Princeton will long remember his time on Lunaapahkiing, along with his daughter Katelyn, for the inaugural Munsee Language and History Symposium in November 2021. Together with Ian McCallum, he spent time with Lunaape language items and Munsee land documents at Firestone Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munsee Three Sisters Farm</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/munsee-three-sisters-farm/</guid>
      <description>The Munsee Three Sisters Farm is created to rebuild community and well-being among Munsee Ramapough clans after centuries of colonial violence, beginning with the Ramapough massacre in 1644 and continuing through a century of state-sanctioned industrial poisoning. The Turtle Clan, for instance, has lived for 56 years in a federal superfund site. The farm cultivates healthy traditionally grown food for distribution at no cost to the community while also earning a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Convocation</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/us-indian-scholars/</guid>
      <description>During the surge of the American Indian Movement in the early 1970s, Princeton hosts the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March. Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Tewa) of Anthropology chairs the event. Considered by some to be the starting point for Native American Studies, a resolution by Native scholars called for an academic discipline that included Indian ways of knowing left out of European-American education.
Princeton prepares to host the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars in March 1970.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Faculty</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/activism/</guid>
      <description>Princeton Anthropology Professor Alfonso Ortiz (Ohkay Owingeh Pueblo) publicly supports the American Indian Movement occupation of Wounded Knee. In 1970, Ortiz, chaired the First Convocation of American Indian Scholars, the first of its kind in Native American history. Arriving from the University of Chicago, where he completed his doctorate, Ortiz became a faculty member in 1967. Working with library curator Alfred Bush, he actively recruits undergraduates from the Southwest, many of whom live on reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Complaints against New Jersey</title>
      <link>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lenapetimetree.indigenous.princeton.edu/leaves/complaints/</guid>
      <description>Alarmed by rising hostilities between colonial and Native peoples across the Delaware River in neighboring Pennsylvania, the Governor of the New Jersey Colony holds meetings in Crosswicks (approximately 18 miles south of Princeton) to hear grievances from Lunaapeew. As missionary John Brainerd (brother of David Brainerd) writes months later, &amp;ldquo;A bill is passed to remove the difficulties which had grown out of impositions upon the Indians when intoxicated, the destruction of deer by traps, and the occupation of lands by the whites which they had not sold.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
