<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oneida on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</title>
    <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/oneida/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oneida on Lunaapahkiing Princeton Timetree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/tags/oneida/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brotherton Refusal and Collapse</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/brotherton-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Brotherton Indians release statement of refusal to leave New Jersey after Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York and invite Brotherton’s members to join them. By 1802, however, the 80 remaining residents successfully petition the state legislature for permission to sell their land and use the funds to move to Oneida Lake in New York.
Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse. Passage about the Oneidas from a 1797 book written by Jedediah Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockbridge</title>
      <link>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/stockbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princeton-cdh.github.io/lenape-timetree-archive/leaves/stockbridge/</guid>
      <description>Some Brotherton Reservation families sell their lands and move to New York State to settle among the Oneidas in Stockbridge, New York (187 miles from Princeton). A few stay behind. The New Jersey Assembly agrees in 1801 to sell the reservation and give profits to remaining tribal members.
Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.Courtesy of&amp;nbsp;Princeton University Library Princeton Herald passage from April 1963 by John Cunningham describing the move from New Jersey to Stockbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
